{
	"description": "Kanji for 日本漢字能力検定 6-10級",
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "お年玉", "answers": [ "おとしだま" ], "comment": "New Year's gift (usu. money given to a child by relatives and visitors)" },
	{ "question": "けいさつ犬", "answers": [ "けいさつけん" ] },
	{ "question": "しごと中", "answers": [ "しごとちゅう" ] },
	{ "question": "じどう車", "answers": [ "じどうしゃ" ] },
	{ "question": "ほうれん草", "answers": [ "ほうれんそう" ], "comment": "spinach" },
	{ "question": "フジ山", "answers": [ "ふじさん" ], "comment": "Mt. Fuji; Fuji-san; Fujiyama" },
	{ "question": "一", "answers": [ "いち", "いつ" ], "comment": "one\nbest\nfirst; foremost\nbeginning; start\nbottom string (on a shamisen, etc.)\none\nfor one thing\nonly\n(not) even\njust (e.g. \"just try it\")\none\nmost\none\none" },
	{ "question": "一つ", "answers": [ "ひとつ" ], "comment": "one\nfor one thing\nonly\n(not) even\njust (e.g. \"just try it\")" },
	{ "question": "一つ目", "answers": [ "ひとつめ" ], "comment": "one-eyed\nfirst (in a series); initial" },
	{ "question": "一人", "answers": [ "ひとり", "いちにん" ], "comment": "one person\nalone; unmarried; solitary" },
	{ "question": "一休み", "answers": [ "ひとやすみ" ], "comment": "(short) rest; breather; break" },
	{ "question": "一円玉", "answers": [ "いちえんだま" ], "comment": "one-yen coin" },
	{ "question": "一口", "answers": [ "ひとくち" ], "comment": "mouthful; morsel; bite\ngulp; sip; draft; draught\none word; in short\none share; one contribution" },
	{ "question": "一名", "answers": [ "いちめい" ], "comment": "one person\nanother name; nickname; alias" },
	{ "question": "一夕", "answers": [ "いっせき" ], "comment": "one evening; some evenings" },
	{ "question": "一天", "answers": [ "いってん" ], "comment": "the whole sky; firmament" },
	{ "question": "一字", "answers": [ "いちじ" ], "comment": "letter; character" },
	{ "question": "一山", "answers": [ "ひとやま", "いっさん" ], "comment": "one mountain\npile (of something); heap; lot (in sale)\nhump; worst part\nlarge profit; killing\nwhole temple complex; all the temples on a mountain\none mountain" },
	{ "question": "一年", "answers": [ "いちねん", "ひととせ" ], "comment": "one year; some time ago" },
	{ "question": "一年生", "answers": [ "いちねんせい" ], "comment": "annual (plant)\nfirst-year student" },
	{ "question": "一手", "answers": [ "いって", "ひとて" ], "comment": "move (in game); method; single-handed; monopoly\none hand\none's own effort" },
	{ "question": "一文", "answers": [ "いちぶん", "いちもん" ], "comment": "(a) sentence\nsomething insignificant; one mon (10th sen)" },
	{ "question": "一日", "answers": [ "いちにち", "ついたち", "いちじつ" ], "comment": "one day\nfirst day of the month\nfirst day of the month\nfirst ten days of the lunar month\nfirst day of the month\nfirst ten days of the lunar month" },
	{ "question": "一月", "answers": [ "いちがつ", "ひとつき" ], "comment": "January\none month" },
	{ "question": "一本", "answers": [ "いっぽん" ], "comment": "one long cylindrical thing; one film, TV show, etc.; one goal, home run, etc.; one telephone call\none version\none book; a certain book\nippon; one point; a blow\nexperienced geisha\nsingle-minded focus on ..." },
	{ "question": "一村", "answers": [ "いっそん" ], "comment": "village; whole village" },
	{ "question": "一校", "answers": [ "いっこう" ], "comment": "whole school; the first proof; one proofreading" },
	{ "question": "一犬", "answers": [ "いっけん" ], "comment": "one dog" },
	{ "question": "一生", "answers": [ "いっしょう" ], "comment": "whole life; a lifetime; all through life; one existence; a generation; an age; the whole world; the era\n(the only, the greatest, etc.) of one's life" },
	{ "question": "一目", "answers": [ "ひとめ", "いちもく" ], "comment": "glance; look; glimpse\ncomplete view; bird's-eye view\nlook; glance\nstone (in the game of go)" },
	{ "question": "一石", "answers": [ "いっせき" ], "comment": "one game (of go)\none koku (measure)" },
	{ "question": "一糸", "answers": [ "いっし" ], "comment": "thread; strand; string" },
	{ "question": "一見", "answers": [ "いっけん", "いちげん" ], "comment": "look; glimpse; glance\napparently; seemingly\nfirst meeting\nfirst visit to inn, restaurant, etc. without an introduction" },
	{ "question": "一足", "answers": [ "いっそく", "ひとあし" ], "comment": "pair (footwear)\nstep\nshort distance; short time" },
	{ "question": "一車", "answers": [ "いっしゃ" ] },
	{ "question": "丁度", "answers": [ "ちょうど" ], "comment": "exactly; precisely; just; right\nas if; as though; quite" },
	{ "question": "七", "answers": [ "なな", "しち" ], "comment": "seven\nhepta-\nseven" },
	{ "question": "七つ", "answers": [ "ななつ" ], "comment": "seven" },
	{ "question": "七夕", "answers": [ "たなばた" ], "comment": "Star Festival (held in July or August); Tanabata; Festival of the Weaver" },
	{ "question": "七日", "answers": [ "なのか", "なぬか" ], "comment": "the seventh day of the month\nseven days" },
	{ "question": "万力", "answers": [ "まんりき" ], "comment": "vise; jack; capstan" },
	{ "question": "三", "answers": [ "さん" ], "comment": "three\ntri-\nthree" },
	{ "question": "三つ", "answers": [ "みっつ", "みつ" ], "comment": "three" },
	{ "question": "三人", "answers": [ "さんにん" ], "comment": "three people" },
	{ "question": "三文", "answers": [ "さんもん", "さんぶん" ], "comment": "cheapness; farthing" },
	{ "question": "三日", "answers": [ "みっか" ], "comment": "the third day of the month\nthree days" },
	{ "question": "上", "answers": [ "うえ", "うわ", "かみ", "じょう" ], "comment": "above; up; over; elder (e.g. daughter)\ntop; summit\nsurface; on\nbefore; previous\nsuperiority; one's superior (i.e. one's elder)\non top of that; besides; what's more\nupon (further inspection, etc.); based on (and occurring after)\nmatters concerning...; as concerns ...\nsince (i.e. \"for that reason\")\nsuffix indicating higher social standing\nplace of one's superior (i.e. the throne)\nemperor; sovereign; shogun; daimyo\nnoblewoman (esp. the wife of a nobleman)\nupper; upward; outer; surface; top\nupper reaches (of a river); upper stream\ntop; upper part; upper half (of the body)\nlong ago\nbeginning; first\nperson of high rank (e.g. the emperor)\ngovernment; imperial court\nimperial capital (i.e. Kyoto); capital region (i.e. Kansai); region (or direction of) the imperial palace\nhead (of a table)\nwife; mistress (of a restaurant)\nfrom the standpoint of; as a matter of (e.g. fact); in the field of; being of the type of\naboard (a ship or vehicle); on top of; on; above\nfirst volume (e.g. book)\nsuperior quality; best; top; high class\ngoing up\ngovernmental; imperial\npresenting; showing\nana- (medical, biol.)" },
	{ "question": "上がり目", "answers": [ "あがりめ" ], "comment": "eyes slanted upward\nrising tendency" },
	{ "question": "上がる", "answers": [ "あがる" ], "comment": "to rise; to go up; to come up; to ascend; to be raised\nto enter (esp. from outdoors); to come in; to go in\nto enter (a school); to advance to the next grade\nto get out (of water); to come ashore\nto increase\nto improve; to make progress\nto be promoted; to advance\nto be made (of profit, etc.)\nto occur (esp. of a favourable result)\nto be adequate (to cover expenses, etc.)\nto be finished; to be done; to be over\n(of rain) to stop; to lift\nto stop (working properly); to cut out; to give out; to die\nto win (in a card game, etc.)\nto be spoken loudly\nto get stage fright\nto be offered (to the gods, etc.)\nto go; to visit\nto eat; to drink\nto be listed (as a candidate)\nto serve (in one's master's home)\nto go north\nindicates completion" },
	{ "question": "上げる", "answers": [ "あげる" ], "comment": "to raise; to elevate\nto do up (one's hair)\nto fly (a kite, etc.); to launch (fireworks, etc.); to surface (a submarine, etc.)\nto land (a boat)\nto show someone (into a room)\nto send someone (away)\nto enrol (one's child in school); to enroll\nto increase (price, quality, status, etc.); to develop (talent, skill); to improve\nto make (a loud sound); to raise (one's voice)\nto earn (something desirable)\nto praise\nto give (an example, etc.); to cite\nto summon up (all of one's energy, etc.)\nto give\nto offer up (incense, a prayer, etc.) to the gods (or Buddha, etc.)\nto bear (a child)\nto conduct (a ceremony, esp. a wedding)\n(of the tide) to come in\nto vomit\nto do for (the sake of someone else)\nto complete ...\nto humbly do ..." },
	{ "question": "上の空", "answers": [ "うわのそら" ], "comment": "inattention; absent-mindedness" },
	{ "question": "上る", "answers": [ "のぼる" ], "comment": "to rise; to go up; to come up; to ascend; to be raised\nto enter (esp. from outdoors); to come in; to go in\nto enter (a school); to advance to the next grade\nto get out (of water); to come ashore\nto increase\nto improve; to make progress\nto be promoted; to advance\nto be made (of profit, etc.)\nto occur (esp. of a favourable result)\nto be adequate (to cover expenses, etc.)\nto be finished; to be done; to be over\n(of rain) to stop; to lift\nto stop (working properly); to cut out; to give out; to die\nto win (in a card game, etc.)\nto be spoken loudly\nto get stage fright\nto be offered (to the gods, etc.)\nto go; to visit\nto eat; to drink\nto be listed (as a candidate)\nto serve (in one's master's home)\nto go north\nindicates completion\nto ascend; to go up; to climb\nto ascend (as a natural process, e.g. the sun); to rise\nto go to (the capital)\nto be promoted\nto add up to\nto advance (in price)\nto swim up (a river); to sail up\nto come up (on the agenda)" },
	{ "question": "上下", "answers": [ "うえした", "しょうか", "じょうか", "じょうげ" ], "comment": "top and bottom; up and down; high and low; above and below; upper and lower ends\nupside-down\ntop and bottom; high and low; above and below; upper and lower ends; up and down\ngoing up and down; rising and falling; fluctuating\ngoing and coming back\nupper and lower classes; ruler and ruled; the government and the people\nfirst and second volumes\nsamurai costume; old ceremonial costume\ntop and bottom; up and down; high and low; above and below; upper and lower ends\ntop and bottom; up and down; high and low; above and below; upper and lower ends\nupper and lower classes; ruler and ruled; the government and the people" },
	{ "question": "上中下", "answers": [ "じょうちゅうげ" ], "comment": "excellent-good-poor; first-second-third (class)\n(in) three volumes (a literary work)" },
	{ "question": "上司", "answers": [ "じょうし" ], "comment": "superior authorities; boss" },
	{ "question": "上手", "answers": [ "じょうず", "うわて", "かみて" ], "comment": "skill; skillful; dexterity\nflattery\nupper part\nupper stream; upper course of a river\nright side of the stage (audience's or camera's POV); stage left (actor's POV)\nskillful (only in comparisons); dexterity (only in comparisons)\nover-arm grip on opponent's belt" },
	{ "question": "上玉", "answers": [ "じょうだま" ], "comment": "fine jewel; best article; pretty woman" },
	{ "question": "上目", "answers": [ "うわめ" ], "comment": "upward glance; upturned eyes\nsuperorder" },
	{ "question": "上空", "answers": [ "じょうくう" ], "comment": "sky; the skies; high-altitude sky; upper air" },
	{ "question": "下", "answers": [ "した", "しも", "もと", "げ" ], "comment": "below; down; under; younger (e.g. daughter)\nbottom\nbeneath; underneath\njust after; right after\ninferiority; one's inferior (i.e. one's junior)\ntrade-in\npreliminary; preparatory\nunder (esp. influence or guidance)\nlowness (of degree, value, etc.); inferiority\nsecond volume (of two); third volume (of three)\nlower reaches (of a river)\nbottom; lower part\nlower half (of the body, esp. the privates); feces (faeces); urine; menses\nend; far from the imperial palace (i.e. far from Kyoto, esp. of western Japan)\ndirty (e.g. dirty jokes, etc.)\nunder (being in said condition or environment)" },
	{ "question": "下がり目", "answers": [ "さがりめ" ], "comment": "eyes slanting downward; decline" },
	{ "question": "下がる", "answers": [ "さがる" ], "comment": "to come down; to go down; to fall; to drop; to sink; to get lower\nto hang; to dangle\nto move back; to step back; to withdraw; to retire\nto deteriorate; to fall off; to be downgraded\nto get closer to the present day\nto go south" },
	{ "question": "下げる", "answers": [ "さげる" ], "comment": "to hang; to suspend; to wear (e.g. decoration)\nto lower; to reduce; to bring down\nto demote; to move back; to pull back\nto clear (plates); to remove (food, etc. from table or altar)" },
	{ "question": "下さる", "answers": [ "くださる" ], "comment": "to give; to confer; to bestow\nto kindly do for one; to oblige; to favour; to favor" },
	{ "question": "下りる", "answers": [ "おりる" ], "comment": "to descend (e.g. a mountain); to go down; to come down\nto alight (e.g. from bus); to get off; to disembark; to dismount\nto step down; to retire; to give up; to quit\nto be granted; to be issued; to be given\nto form (of frost, dew, mist, etc.)\nto be passed (from the body; e.g. of a roundworm)" },
	{ "question": "下る", "answers": [ "くだる" ], "comment": "to come down; to go down; to fall; to drop; to sink; to get lower\nto hang; to dangle\nto move back; to step back; to withdraw; to retire\nto deteriorate; to fall off; to be downgraded\nto get closer to the present day\nto go south\nto descend; to go down; to come down\nto be handed down (of an order, judgment, etc.)\nto pass (of time)\nto surrender; to capitulate\n(often in neg. form) to be less than; to be inferior to\nto have the runs; to have diarrhea\nto pass (in stool); to be discharged from the body" },
	{ "question": "下ろす", "answers": [ "おろす" ], "comment": "to take down (e.g. flag); to launch (e.g. boat); to drop; to lower (e.g. ladder); to let (a person) off; to unload; to discharge\nto drop off (a passenger from a vehicle); to let (a person) off\nto withdraw money from an account\nto wear (clothing) for the first time\nto fillet (e.g. a fish)" },
	{ "question": "下山", "answers": [ "げざん", "げさん" ], "comment": "descending (mountain)" },
	{ "question": "下手", "answers": [ "へた", "したて", "したで", "しもて" ], "comment": "humble position; inferior\nunderarm grip on opponent's belt\nlower part; foot; lower direction\nleft part of the stage (audience's or camera's POV); stage right (actor's POV)\nunskillful; poor; awkward\nimprudent; untactful" },
	{ "question": "下校", "answers": [ "げこう" ], "comment": "coming home from school" },
	{ "question": "下町", "answers": [ "したまち" ], "comment": "low-lying part of a city (usu. containing shops, factories, etc.)\nShitamachi (low-lying area of eastern Tokyo near Tokyo Bay, incl. Asakusa, Shitaya, Kanda, Fukugawa, Honjo, Nihonbashi, Kyobashi and surrounds)" },
	{ "question": "下目", "answers": [ "しため" ], "comment": "downward glance; contemptuous look\ninfraorder" },
	{ "question": "下草", "answers": [ "したくさ" ], "comment": "undergrowth; weeds beneath a tree" },
	{ "question": "下見", "answers": [ "したみ" ], "comment": "preview; preliminary inspection\npreparatory reading; preparation for a lesson; rehearsal\nsiding (on a house); clapboard; weatherboard" },
	{ "question": "下車", "answers": [ "げしゃ" ], "comment": "alighting (from train, bus, etc.); getting off" },
	{ "question": "不満", "answers": [ "ふまん" ], "comment": "dissatisfaction; displeasure; discontent; complaints; unhappiness; disgruntled" },
	{ "question": "不燃", "answers": [ "ふねん" ], "comment": "incombustibility" },
	{ "question": "中", "answers": [ "なか", "ちゅう" ], "comment": "inside; in\namong; within\ncenter (centre); middle\nduring; while\ninside; within\nwhile\namong; amongst; between\nwe (referring to one's in-group, e.g. company, etc.); our\nmy spouse\nimperial palace grounds\nemperor\nI (primarily used by women and children); me\nmedium; average; middle\nmoderation\nmiddle school\nChina\nvolume two (of three)\nduring (a certain time when one did or is doing something); under (construction, etc.); while\nin; out of (e.g. three out of ten people)\nthrough; throughout; in the course of\nall over or throughout (e.g. a place)\nred dragon tile\nwinning hand with a pung (or kong) of red dragon tiles" },
	{ "question": "中天", "answers": [ "ちゅうてん" ], "comment": "mid-air; mid-heaven; zenith" },
	{ "question": "中学校", "answers": [ "ちゅうがっこう" ], "comment": "junior high school; middle school; lower secondary school" },
	{ "question": "中学生", "answers": [ "ちゅうがくせい" ], "comment": "junior high school student; middle school pupil" },
	{ "question": "中断", "answers": [ "ちゅうだん" ], "comment": "interruption; suspension; break" },
	{ "question": "中正", "answers": [ "ちゅうせい" ], "comment": "impartiality; fairness" },
	{ "question": "中空", "answers": [ "ちゅうくう", "なかぞら" ], "comment": "hollow; emptiness\nmid-air; the air" },
	{ "question": "中立", "answers": [ "ちゅうりつ" ], "comment": "neutrality\nbreak between the light meal and the actual serving of tea (during a formal tea ceremony)" },
	{ "question": "中耳", "answers": [ "ちゅうじ" ], "comment": "middle ear; tympanum" },
	{ "question": "丸い", "answers": [ "まるい" ], "comment": "round; circular; spherical\nharmonious; calm" },
	{ "question": "乗車", "answers": [ "じょうしゃ" ], "comment": "taking a train, bus, etc.; entraining" },
	{ "question": "九", "answers": [ "きゅう", "く" ], "comment": "nine\nnine" },
	{ "question": "九つ", "answers": [ "ここのつ" ], "comment": "nine" },
	{ "question": "九日", "answers": [ "ここのか" ], "comment": "the ninth day of the month\nnine days" },
	{ "question": "予報", "answers": [ "よほう" ], "comment": "forecast; prediction" },
	{ "question": "争い", "answers": [ "あらそい" ], "comment": "dispute; strife; quarrel; dissension; conflict; rivalry; contest" },
	{ "question": "二", "answers": [ "に" ], "comment": "two\ntwo" },
	{ "question": "二つ", "answers": [ "ふたつ" ], "comment": "two" },
	{ "question": "二の足", "answers": [ "にのあし" ], "comment": "hesitation" },
	{ "question": "二人", "answers": [ "ふたり", "ににん" ], "comment": "two persons; two people; pair; couple" },
	{ "question": "二年", "answers": [ "にねん" ] },
	{ "question": "二手", "answers": [ "ふたて" ], "comment": "two groups; two bands" },
	{ "question": "二日", "answers": [ "ふつか" ], "comment": "second day of the month\ntwo days" },
	{ "question": "二目", "answers": [ "ふため", "にもく" ], "comment": "for a second time" },
	{ "question": "二足", "answers": [ "にそく" ], "comment": "two legs; two feet\ntwo pairs" },
	{ "question": "二階", "answers": [ "にかい" ], "comment": "second floor; upstairs" },
	{ "question": "五", "answers": [ "ご" ], "comment": "five\nfive" },
	{ "question": "五つ", "answers": [ "いつつ" ], "comment": "five" },
	{ "question": "五日", "answers": [ "いつか" ], "comment": "the fifth day of the month\nfive days" },
	{ "question": "交わる", "answers": [ "まじわる" ], "comment": "to cross; to intersect; to join; to meet\nto associate with; to mingle with; to consort with\nto have a sexual relationship; to copulate" },
	{ "question": "人", "answers": [ "ひと" ], "comment": "-ian (e.g. Italian); -ite (e.g. Tokyoite); indicates nationality, race, origin, etc.\n-er (e.g. performer, etc.); person working with ...; indicates expertise (in a certain field)\n(usu. in compound words) man; person; people\nperson\nman; person\nhuman being; mankind; people\nhuman (Homo sapiens); humans as a species\ncharacter; personality\nman of talent; true man\nanother person; other people; others\nadult\ncounter for people\nperson" },
	{ "question": "人力", "answers": [ "じんりょく", "じんりき" ], "comment": "human power; human strength; human effort; human agency" },
	{ "question": "人口", "answers": [ "じんこう" ], "comment": "population\ncommon talk" },
	{ "question": "人名", "answers": [ "じんめい" ], "comment": "person's name" },
	{ "question": "人山", "answers": [ "ひとやま" ], "comment": "crowd of people" },
	{ "question": "人形", "answers": [ "にんぎょう" ], "comment": "doll; puppet; figure" },
	{ "question": "人手", "answers": [ "ひとで" ], "comment": "starfish; sea star; asteroid; any echinoderm of the class Asteroidea\nnorthern Pacific seastar (Asterias amurensis)\nsomeone else's hands; other hands\nhand (worker); aide\nlabor; work; manpower; effort\nhelp; assistance" },
	{ "question": "人文", "answers": [ "じんぶん", "じんもん" ], "comment": "humanity; civilization; civilisation; culture" },
	{ "question": "人気", "answers": [ "にんき", "ひとけ", "じんき" ], "comment": "popularity; public favor\ncondition (e.g. market); tone; character; nature\nsign of life; human presence\nhumanity; humaneness\nprevailing mood of a locality; emotional climate of a district" },
	{ "question": "人生", "answers": [ "じんせい" ], "comment": "(human) life (i.e. conception to death)" },
	{ "question": "人目", "answers": [ "ひとめ", "じんもく" ], "comment": "public gaze; public notice; attention" },
	{ "question": "人足", "answers": [ "ひとあし", "にんそく" ], "comment": "coolie; laborer; labourer; carrier\npedestrian traffic\nkanji \"legs radical\" (radical 10)" },
	{ "question": "今後", "answers": [ "こんご" ], "comment": "from now on; hereafter" },
	{ "question": "仏", "answers": [ "ほとけ" ], "comment": "France\nBuddha; Buddhism\nBuddha; merciful person; Buddhist image\nthe dead; dead person; spirit of the dead" },
	{ "question": "仕える", "answers": [ "つかえる" ], "comment": "to serve; to work for; to attend" },
	{ "question": "仕事", "answers": [ "しごと" ], "comment": "work; job; business; occupation; employment; vocation; task\nwork" },
	{ "question": "以前", "answers": [ "いぜん" ], "comment": "ago; since; before; previous" },
	{ "question": "仲", "answers": [ "なか" ], "comment": "relation; relationship\nbroker; brokerage; brokerage fee" },
	{ "question": "任務", "answers": [ "にんむ" ], "comment": "duty; function; office; mission; task" },
	{ "question": "任期", "answers": [ "にんき" ], "comment": "term of office" },
	{ "question": "休けい", "answers": [ "きゅうけい" ], "comment": "rest; break; recess; intermission" },
	{ "question": "休まる", "answers": [ "やすまる" ], "comment": "to be rested; to feel at ease; to repose; to be relieved" },
	{ "question": "休む", "answers": [ "やすむ" ], "comment": "to be absent; to take a day off\nto rest; to have a break\nto go to bed; to (lie down to) sleep; to turn in; to retire\nto stop doing some ongoing activity for a time; to suspend business" },
	{ "question": "休める", "answers": [ "やすめる" ], "comment": "to rest; to suspend; to give relief" },
	{ "question": "休学", "answers": [ "きゅうがく" ], "comment": "temporary absence from school" },
	{ "question": "休日", "answers": [ "きゅうじつ" ], "comment": "holiday; day off" },
	{ "question": "休校", "answers": [ "きゅうこう" ], "comment": "closing school (temporarily); dropping one's studies" },
	{ "question": "会社", "answers": [ "かいしゃ" ], "comment": "company; corporation\nworkplace" },
	{ "question": "低下", "answers": [ "ていか" ], "comment": "fall; decline; lowering; deterioration; degradation" },
	{ "question": "体積", "answers": [ "たいせき" ], "comment": "capacity; volume" },
	{ "question": "何回", "answers": [ "なんかい" ], "comment": "how many times?" },
	{ "question": "作る", "answers": [ "つくる" ], "comment": "to make; to produce; to manufacture; to build; to construct\nto prepare (food); to brew (alcohol)\nto raise; to grow; to cultivate; to train\nto till\nto draw up (a document); to make out; to prepare; to write\nto create (an artistic work, etc.); to compose\nto coin (a phrase); to organize; to organise; to establish; to found\nto have (a child)\nto make up (one's face, etc.)\nto fabricate (an excuse, etc.)\nto form (a line, etc.)\nto set (a record)\nto commit (a sin, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "使用", "answers": [ "しよう" ], "comment": "use; application; employment; utilization; utilisation" },
	{ "question": "例える", "answers": [ "たとえる" ], "comment": "to compare; to liken; to speak figuratively; to illustrate; to use a simile" },
	{ "question": "保管", "answers": [ "ほかん" ], "comment": "charge; custody; safekeeping; deposit; storage" },
	{ "question": "借りる", "answers": [ "かりる" ], "comment": "to borrow; to have a loan\nto rent; to hire" },
	{ "question": "停車", "answers": [ "ていしゃ" ], "comment": "stopping (e.g. train)" },
	{ "question": "健やか", "answers": [ "すこやか" ], "comment": "vigorous; healthy; sound" },
	{ "question": "備える", "answers": [ "そなえる" ], "comment": "to furnish; to provide for; to equip; to install\nto have ready; to prepare for\nto possess (all that is needed); to be endowed with; to be armed with\nto be born with; to have since birth" },
	{ "question": "備品", "answers": [ "びひん" ], "comment": "fixtures; furnishings; equipment" },
	{ "question": "元気", "answers": [ "げんき" ], "comment": "lively; full of spirit; energetic; vigorous; vital; spirited\nhealthy; well; fit; in good health" },
	{ "question": "兄", "answers": [ "あに" ], "comment": "elder brother; older brother\nelder brother\npronoun or suffix used in reference to an older brother figure; Mister; Mr\nused after the name of someone who is an older brother figure\nused with various honorifics to mean (older) brother\neldest son\nolder brother; older sister\nolder person\nhead of a clan; head of a region\nskilled craftsman" },
	{ "question": "先", "answers": [ "さき", "せん" ], "comment": "previous; prior; former; first; earlier; some time ago; preceding\npoint (e.g. pencil); tip; end; nozzle\nhead (of a line); front\nahead; the other side\nthe future; hereafter\ndestination\nthe other party\nformer; previous; old\nfirst move (in go, shogi, etc.); opening move" },
	{ "question": "先々", "answers": [ "さきざき" ], "comment": "distant future; inevitable future\nplaces one goes to" },
	{ "question": "先人", "answers": [ "せんじん" ], "comment": "predecessor; pioneer; ancestor" },
	{ "question": "先天", "answers": [ "せんてん" ], "comment": "inherent; innate" },
	{ "question": "先年", "answers": [ "せんねん" ], "comment": "former years; formerly; a few years ago" },
	{ "question": "先手", "answers": [ "せんて", "さきて" ], "comment": "front lines; vanguard\nfirst move (in go, shogi, etc.); moving first; person with the first move\nforestalling; (seizing the) initiative" },
	{ "question": "先日", "answers": [ "せんじつ" ], "comment": "the other day; a few days ago" },
	{ "question": "先月", "answers": [ "せんげつ" ], "comment": "last month" },
	{ "question": "先生", "answers": [ "せんせい" ], "comment": "teacher; master; doctor\nwith names of teachers, etc. as an honorific\nprevious existence\nboy" },
	{ "question": "光る", "answers": [ "ひかる" ], "comment": "to shine; to glitter; to be bright" },
	{ "question": "光景", "answers": [ "こうけい" ], "comment": "scene; spectacle; sight; view" },
	{ "question": "入り口", "answers": [ "いりぐち" ], "comment": "entrance; entry; gate; approach; mouth" },
	{ "question": "入る", "answers": [ "はいる", "いる" ], "comment": "to get in; to go in; to come in; to flow into; to set; to set in\nto enter; to go into\nto break into\nto join; to enroll\nto contain; to hold; to accommodate\nto have (an income of)\nto get; to receive; to score" },
	{ "question": "入れる", "answers": [ "いれる" ], "comment": "to put in; to let in; to take in; to bring in; to insert; to set (a jewel, etc.); to ink in (e.g. a tattoo)\nto admit; to accept; to employ; to hire\nto accept; to comply; to grant; to adopt (a policy, etc.); to take (advice, etc.); to listen to; to pay attention to\nto include\nto pay (one's rent, etc.)\nto cast (a vote)\nto make (tea, coffee, etc.)\nto turn on (a switch, etc.)\nto send (a fax); to call" },
	{ "question": "入力", "answers": [ "にゅうりょく" ], "comment": "input; (data) entry" },
	{ "question": "入学", "answers": [ "にゅうがく" ], "comment": "entry to school or university; matriculation; enrolment (in university, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "入手", "answers": [ "にゅうしゅ" ], "comment": "acquisition; obtaining; coming to hand" },
	{ "question": "入浴", "answers": [ "にゅうよく" ], "comment": "bathing\nto bathe; to take a bath; to enter a bath" },
	{ "question": "入賞", "answers": [ "にゅうしょう" ], "comment": "winning a prize or place (in a contest)" },
	{ "question": "入金", "answers": [ "にゅうきん" ], "comment": "deposit; payment; money received; money due" },
	{ "question": "全く", "answers": [ "まったく" ], "comment": "really; truly; entirely; completely; wholly; perfectly\nindeed\ngood grief (expression of exasperation)" },
	{ "question": "全員", "answers": [ "ぜんいん" ], "comment": "all members (unanimity); all hands; the whole crew; everyone; everybody" },
	{ "question": "八", "answers": [ "はち" ], "comment": "eight\neight" },
	{ "question": "八つ", "answers": [ "やっつ", "やつ" ], "comment": "eight" },
	{ "question": "八日", "answers": [ "ようか" ], "comment": "the eighth day of the month\neight days" },
	{ "question": "公園", "answers": [ "こうえん" ], "comment": "(public) park" },
	{ "question": "六", "answers": [ "ろく" ], "comment": "six\nsix" },
	{ "question": "六つ", "answers": [ "むっつ", "むつ" ], "comment": "six" },
	{ "question": "六日", "answers": [ "むいか" ], "comment": "sixth day of the month\nsix days" },
	{ "question": "円", "answers": [ "えん" ], "comment": "yen; Japanese monetary unit\ncircle\ncircle\nentirety; whole; full; complete\nmoney; dough; moola\nenclosure inside a castle's walls\nsoft-shelled turtle\nsuffix for ship names; suffix for names of people (esp. infants); suffix for names of swords, armour, musical instruments, etc.; suffix for names of dogs, horses, etc." },
	{ "question": "円い", "answers": [ "まるい" ], "comment": "round; circular; spherical\nharmonious; calm" },
	{ "question": "円石", "answers": [ "えんせき" ], "comment": "round stone; pebble; boulder; cobblestone; cobble" },
	{ "question": "写真", "answers": [ "しゃしん" ], "comment": "photograph; photo; picture; snapshot; snap\nmovie" },
	{ "question": "出", "answers": [ "で" ], "comment": "coming out; going out; outflow; efflux; rising (of the sun or moon)\nattending (work); appearing (on stage); one's turn to go on\nstart; beginning\norigins; background; person (or item) originating from ...; graduate of ...; native of ...; member of ... (lineage)\narchitectural member that projects outward\nhighest point of the stern of a ship\namount (comprising something); amount of time or effort required to do something\ncoming out; emerging\nbeing born into (a certain family); being a native of (a particular place)" },
	{ "question": "出し入れ", "answers": [ "だしいれ" ], "comment": "deposit and withdraw; taking in and out" },
	{ "question": "出す", "answers": [ "だす" ], "comment": "to take out; to get out\nto put out; to reveal; to show\nto submit (e.g. thesis); to turn in\nto publish; to make public\nto send (e.g. letter)\nto produce (a sound); to start (fire)\nto serve (food)\nto begin ...; to start to ...; to burst into ..." },
	{ "question": "出る", "answers": [ "でる" ], "comment": "to leave; to exit; to go out; to come out; to get out\nto leave (on a journey); to depart; to start out; to set out\nto move forward\nto come to; to get to; to lead to; to reach\nto appear; to come out; to emerge; to surface; to come forth; to turn up; to be found; to be detected; to be discovered; to be exposed; to show; to be exhibited; to be on display\nto appear (in print); to be published; to be announced; to be issued; to be listed; to come out\nto attend; to participate; to take part; to enter (an event); to play in; to perform\nto be stated; to be expressed; to come up; to be brought up; to be raised\nto sell\nto exceed; to go over\nto stick out; to protrude\nto break out; to occur; to start; to originate\nto be produced\nto come from; to be derived from\nto be given; to get; to receive; to be offered; to be provided; to be presented; to be submitted; to be handed in; to be turned in; to be paid\nto answer (phone, door, etc.); to get\nto assume (an attitude); to act; to behave\nto pick up (speed, etc.); to gain\nto flow (e.g. tears); to run; to bleed\nto graduate" },
	{ "question": "出入", "answers": [ "しゅつにゅう" ], "comment": "in and out; income and expenses; free associations; run of the house" },
	{ "question": "出入り", "answers": [ "でいり", "ではいり" ], "comment": "in and out; coming and going; free association; income and expenditure; debits and credit" },
	{ "question": "出力", "answers": [ "しゅつりょく" ], "comment": "output (electrical, signal, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "出口", "answers": [ "でぐち" ], "comment": "exit; gateway; way out; outlet; leak; vent" },
	{ "question": "出土", "answers": [ "しゅつど" ], "comment": "archeological excavation (archaeological)" },
	{ "question": "出場", "answers": [ "しゅつじょう" ], "comment": "(stage) appearance; performance\nparticipation (e.g. in a tournament)\none's time (e.g. to go on stage); one's turn\nsource; origin; place of production" },
	{ "question": "出水", "answers": [ "しゅっすい", "でみず" ], "comment": "flood; freshet; inundation" },
	{ "question": "出火", "answers": [ "しゅっか" ], "comment": "outbreak of fire" },
	{ "question": "出生", "answers": [ "しゅっしょう", "しゅっせい" ], "comment": "birth" },
	{ "question": "出産", "answers": [ "しゅっさん" ], "comment": "childbirth; (giving) birth; delivery; parturition; confinement\nproduction (of goods)" },
	{ "question": "出番", "answers": [ "でばん" ], "comment": "one's turn; one's shift\none's turn on stage; screen time; screentime" },
	{ "question": "出目", "answers": [ "でめ" ], "comment": "protruding eyes\nnumber of pips visible after a throw of the dice" },
	{ "question": "出航", "answers": [ "しゅっこう" ], "comment": "departure; sailing; shipping out; putting out to sea; takeoff; leaving port" },
	{ "question": "出足", "answers": [ "であし" ], "comment": "turnout (of people)\nstart (e.g. race, campaign, term of office)\nconstant forward movement; initial charge; dash" },
	{ "question": "出金", "answers": [ "しゅっきん" ], "comment": "withdrawal (of money); payment; contribution; investment; financing" },
	{ "question": "刀", "answers": [ "かたな" ], "comment": "(single-edged) sword; katana\ndagger; knife\nscalpel" },
	{ "question": "切れる", "answers": [ "きれる" ], "comment": "to break; to snap; to be cut; to split; to crack\nto be injured\nto wear out; to be worn out\nto break; to burst; to collapse\nto wear off; to stop working; to go dead\nto expire (time limit, etc.); to run out; to become due\nto run out (of stock, etc.); to be exhausted; to be used up; to be sold out; to be out of\nto be broken off (e.g. of a relationship); to break up; to have severed ties; to be cut off; to be disconnected\nto cut well; to be sharp\nto be sharp-minded; to be keen; to be shrewd; to be quick-witted; to be able\nto be short of; to drop under (a certain figure); to beat (e.g. a record time)\nto dry off\nto curve; to veer\nto shuffle (cards)\nto get angry; to snap; to blow one's top; to lose one's temper; to flip\nto be able to do completely" },
	{ "question": "初版", "answers": [ "しょはん" ], "comment": "first edition" },
	{ "question": "判断", "answers": [ "はんだん" ], "comment": "judgment; judgement; decision; conclusion; adjudication\ndivination\njudgement" },
	{ "question": "別人", "answers": [ "べつじん" ], "comment": "different person; someone else; changed man" },
	{ "question": "利益", "answers": [ "りえき" ], "comment": "profit; gains\nbenefit; advantage; interest (of the public, etc.)\ngrace (of God, Buddha, etc.) (esp. as attained through rightful actions, prayer, adherence to one's faith, etc.); blessing; miracle" },
	{ "question": "力", "answers": [ "ちから" ], "comment": "force; strength; might; vigour (vigor); energy\ncapability; ability; proficiency; capacity; faculty\nefficacy; effect\neffort; endeavours (endeavors); exertions\npower; authority; influence; good offices; agency\nsupport; help; aid; assistance\nstress; emphasis\nmeans; resources\nstrength; power; proficiency; ability\nthe strength of ... people; the strength of ... men\nstrength; power; proficiency; ability" },
	{ "question": "力学", "answers": [ "りきがく" ], "comment": "mechanics; dynamics" },
	{ "question": "加熱", "answers": [ "かねつ" ], "comment": "heating; application of heat" },
	{ "question": "助ける", "answers": [ "たすける" ], "comment": "to save; to rescue\nto help; to assist\nto aid; to contribute (financially)\nto facilitate; to stimulate" },
	{ "question": "努力", "answers": [ "どりょく" ], "comment": "great effort; exertion; endeavour; endeavor; effort" },
	{ "question": "勇気", "answers": [ "ゆうき" ], "comment": "courage; bravery; valour; valor; nerve; boldness" },
	{ "question": "勝負", "answers": [ "しょうぶ" ], "comment": "victory or defeat; match; contest; game; bout" },
	{ "question": "勢力", "answers": [ "せいりょく" ], "comment": "influence; power; might; strength; potency; force; energy" },
	{ "question": "包囲", "answers": [ "ほうい" ], "comment": "siege; encirclement; envelopment; surrounding; besiegement" },
	{ "question": "北", "answers": [ "きた" ], "comment": "north\nthe North; northern territories\nNorth Korea\nnorth wind" },
	{ "question": "北極", "answers": [ "ほっきょく" ], "comment": "North Pole\nthe Arctic" },
	{ "question": "医師", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "doctor; physician\ndoctor" },
	{ "question": "医者", "answers": [ "いしゃ" ], "comment": "(medical) doctor; physician" },
	{ "question": "十", "answers": [ "じゅう", "とお" ], "comment": "ten\nten" },
	{ "question": "十人力", "answers": [ "じゅうにんりき" ], "comment": "the strength of ten" },
	{ "question": "十字", "answers": [ "じゅうじ" ], "comment": "cross; crossed; cruciform" },
	{ "question": "十日", "answers": [ "とおか" ], "comment": "the tenth day of the month\nten days" },
	{ "question": "十目", "answers": [ "じゅうもく" ], "comment": "all eyes" },
	{ "question": "千", "answers": [ "せん" ], "comment": "1,000; thousand" },
	{ "question": "千人", "answers": [ "せんにん" ] },
	{ "question": "千人力", "answers": [ "せんにんりき" ], "comment": "strength of a thousand men" },
	{ "question": "千円", "answers": [ "せんえん" ], "comment": "1000 yen" },
	{ "question": "午後", "answers": [ "ごご" ], "comment": "afternoon; p.m." },
	{ "question": "半分", "answers": [ "はんぶん" ], "comment": "half\nhalf minute" },
	{ "question": "卒業", "answers": [ "そつぎょう" ], "comment": "graduation; completion (e.g. of a course)\noutgrowing something; moving on" },
	{ "question": "印刷", "answers": [ "いんさつ" ], "comment": "printing" },
	{ "question": "友人", "answers": [ "ゆうじん" ], "comment": "friend" },
	{ "question": "反対", "answers": [ "はんたい" ], "comment": "opposition; resistance; antagonism; hostility; objection; dissension\nreverse; opposite; vice versa; contrast" },
	{ "question": "受理", "answers": [ "じゅり" ], "comment": "acceptance" },
	{ "question": "受験", "answers": [ "じゅけん" ], "comment": "taking an examination (esp. school and university entrance)" },
	{ "question": "口", "answers": [ "くち" ], "comment": "mouth\nopening; hole; gap; orifice\nmouth (of a bottle); spout; nozzle; mouthpiece\ngate; door; entrance; exit\nspeaking; speech; talk (i.e. gossip)\ntaste; palate\nmouth (to feed)\nopening (i.e. vacancy); available position\ninvitation; summons\nkind; sort; type\nopening (i.e. beginning)\ncounter for mouthfuls, shares (of money), and swords\nmouth; speech\ncounter for people or implements" },
	{ "question": "口々", "answers": [ "くちぐち" ], "comment": "each entrance; every mouth" },
	{ "question": "口上", "answers": [ "こうじょう" ], "comment": "vocal message; speech; statement\nprologue at the start of a kabuki performance" },
	{ "question": "口下手", "answers": [ "くちべた" ], "comment": "defective speech; slowness of speech; poor talker; tongue-tied person" },
	{ "question": "口中", "answers": [ "こうちゅう" ], "comment": "interior of the mouth; oral cavity" },
	{ "question": "口出し", "answers": [ "くちだし" ], "comment": "interference; meddling; butting in" },
	{ "question": "口火", "answers": [ "くちび" ], "comment": "fuse; pilot light\ncause (of a war, argument, revolt, etc.); origin; trigger" },
	{ "question": "口笛", "answers": [ "くちぶえ" ], "comment": "whistle (sound made with the lips)" },
	{ "question": "口車", "answers": [ "くちぐるま" ], "comment": "cajolery; wheedling" },
	{ "question": "口金", "answers": [ "くちがね" ], "comment": "(metal) cap\nclasp\nmouthpiece\nsocket (for light, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "古い", "answers": [ "ふるい" ], "comment": "old (not person); aged; ancient; antiquated; stale; threadbare; outmoded; obsolete article" },
	{ "question": "史実", "answers": [ "しじつ" ], "comment": "historical fact" },
	{ "question": "右", "answers": [ "みぎ" ], "comment": "right; right hand side\nafore-mentioned (esp. in vertical Japanese writing); foregoing; forgoing; above" },
	{ "question": "右手", "answers": [ "みぎて", "めて" ], "comment": "right hand\nright-hand side; right-hand direction; (on) the right" },
	{ "question": "右足", "answers": [ "みぎあし", "うそく" ], "comment": "right foot\nright leg" },
	{ "question": "号泣", "answers": [ "ごうきゅう" ], "comment": "crying aloud; lamentation; wailing" },
	{ "question": "各自", "answers": [ "かくじ" ], "comment": "each (person); everyone; individual; respective" },
	{ "question": "合図", "answers": [ "あいず" ], "comment": "sign; signal" },
	{ "question": "同情", "answers": [ "どうじょう" ], "comment": "sympathy; compassion; feeling pity for" },
	{ "question": "名", "answers": [ "な", "めい" ], "comment": "name; given name\ntitle\nfame; renown; reputation\npretext; pretense; justification; appearance\ncounter for people (usu. seating, reservations and such)\nfirst name\nfamous; great\nname\nnoun" },
	{ "question": "名人", "answers": [ "めいじん" ], "comment": "master; expert" },
	{ "question": "名入り", "answers": [ "ないり" ] },
	{ "question": "名字", "answers": [ "みょうじ" ], "comment": "surname; family name" },
	{ "question": "名手", "answers": [ "めいしゅ" ], "comment": "master; expert\nexpert board game player (chess, go, shogi, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "名文", "answers": [ "めいぶん" ], "comment": "famous literary composition" },
	{ "question": "名水", "answers": [ "めいすい" ], "comment": "famous mineral water; famous spring; famous river" },
	{ "question": "名目", "answers": [ "めいもく", "みょうもく" ], "comment": "name; title; appellation; (something) nominal\n(under the) pretext (of); pretense" },
	{ "question": "名目上", "answers": [ "めいもくじょう" ], "comment": "in name; on paper" },
	{ "question": "名花", "answers": [ "めいか" ], "comment": "celebrated flower; beautiful woman" },
	{ "question": "向上", "answers": [ "こうじょう" ], "comment": "elevation; rise; improvement; advancement; progress" },
	{ "question": "君主", "answers": [ "くんしゅ" ], "comment": "ruler; monarch; sovereign" },
	{ "question": "告げる", "answers": [ "つげる" ], "comment": "to tell; to inform; to announce\nto indicate; to signal; to mark" },
	{ "question": "命令", "answers": [ "めいれい" ], "comment": "order; command; decree; directive\n(software) instruction; statement" },
	{ "question": "商店", "answers": [ "しょうてん" ], "comment": "shop; small store; business; firm" },
	{ "question": "喜ぶ", "answers": [ "よろこぶ" ], "comment": "to be delighted; to be glad; to be pleased\nto congratulate\nto gratefully accept" },
	{ "question": "営む", "answers": [ "いとなむ" ], "comment": "to run (a business); to operate; to conduct; to practice (law, medicine, etc.)\nto carry out; to perform; to lead (a life)\nto hold (a Buddhist or Shinto ceremony)" },
	{ "question": "営業", "answers": [ "えいぎょう" ], "comment": "business; trade; sales; operations" },
	{ "question": "四", "answers": [ "よん", "し" ], "comment": "four\nfour" },
	{ "question": "四つ", "answers": [ "よっつ", "よつ" ], "comment": "four" },
	{ "question": "四つ足", "answers": [ "よつあし" ], "comment": "four-footed (animal)" },
	{ "question": "四日", "answers": [ "よっか" ], "comment": "fourth day of the month\nfour days" },
	{ "question": "四足", "answers": [ "しそく" ], "comment": "four legs; four-legged; quadruped" },
	{ "question": "団結", "answers": [ "だんけつ" ], "comment": "unity; union; combination; teaming up" },
	{ "question": "図", "answers": [ "ず" ], "comment": "drawing; picture; diagram; figure; illustration; chart; graph\nsight; scene" },
	{ "question": "土", "answers": [ "つち" ], "comment": "earth; soil; dirt; clay; mud\nthe earth (historically, esp. as opposed to the heavens); the ground; the land\nlow-quality torinoko-gami (containing mud)\n(period of) refraining from construction in the direction of the god of the earth (in Onmyōdō)\nSaturday\nearth (third of the five elements)\nTurkey\nsoil (esp. reddish soil)" },
	{ "question": "土足", "answers": [ "どそく" ], "comment": "shod feet\nmuddy feet; dirty feet" },
	{ "question": "圧力", "answers": [ "あつりょく" ], "comment": "pressure; stress\ncoercion; arm-twisting" },
	{ "question": "地区", "answers": [ "ちく" ], "comment": "district; section; sector" },
	{ "question": "坂", "answers": [ "さか" ], "comment": "slope; hill" },
	{ "question": "報告", "answers": [ "ほうこく" ], "comment": "report; information" },
	{ "question": "場", "answers": [ "じょう" ], "comment": "place; spot; space\nfield; discipline; sphere; realm\noccasion; situation\nscene (of a play, movie, etc.)\nsession (of the stock market)\narea in which cards are laid out (in a card game)\nround (i.e. east, south, etc.)\nfield\nfield (gestalt psychology)\nplace; spot; grounds; arena; stadium; range; course" },
	{ "question": "塩分", "answers": [ "えんぶん" ], "comment": "salt; salt content" },
	{ "question": "境目", "answers": [ "さかいめ" ], "comment": "borderline; boundary" },
	{ "question": "墓", "answers": [ "はか" ], "comment": "gravesite; tomb" },
	{ "question": "声", "answers": [ "こえ" ], "comment": "voice" },
	{ "question": "変動", "answers": [ "へんどう" ], "comment": "change; fluctuation" },
	{ "question": "夏", "answers": [ "なつ" ], "comment": "summer\nXia (dynasty of China; perhaps mythological)\nsummer (on the lunisolar calendar: 16th day of the 4th month to the 15th day of the 7th month)" },
	{ "question": "夕", "answers": [ "ゆう" ], "comment": "18 ml (one-tenth of a go)\n0.033 meters square (one-hundredth of a tsubo)\ndip; ladle\nevening\nlast night" },
	{ "question": "夕べ", "answers": [ "ゆうべ" ], "comment": "evening\nlast night" },
	{ "question": "夕日", "answers": [ "ゆうひ" ], "comment": "evening sun; setting sun" },
	{ "question": "夕月", "answers": [ "ゆうづき" ], "comment": "the evening moon" },
	{ "question": "夕立", "answers": [ "ゆうだち" ], "comment": "(sudden) evening shower (rain)" },
	{ "question": "外出", "answers": [ "がいしゅつ" ], "comment": "going out; outing; leaving (one's home, office, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "多い", "answers": [ "おおい" ], "comment": "many; numerous; a lot\nlarge quantity; large amount\nfrequent; common" },
	{ "question": "夢中", "answers": [ "むちゅう" ], "comment": "daze; (in a) trance; ecstasy; delirium; engrossment; within a (deep) dream" },
	{ "question": "大", "answers": [ "だい" ], "comment": "big; large\nthe large part of\nbig; large; great\napproximate size; no larger than\n-university\nlarge (e.g. serving size); loud (e.g. volume setting)\ngreat; grand; large\ngreater (of equal court ranks); upper; senior\na great deal; very much\ngreater (of equal court ranks); upper; senior\na great deal; very much" },
	{ "question": "大いに", "answers": [ "おおいに" ], "comment": "very; much; greatly; a lot of" },
	{ "question": "大きい", "answers": [ "おおきい" ], "comment": "big; large; great; loud" },
	{ "question": "大きな", "answers": [ "おおきな" ], "comment": "big; large; great" },
	{ "question": "大人", "answers": [ "おとな", "たいじん", "だいにん" ], "comment": "adult\nman of substance or virtue; gentleman\ngiant\nadult" },
	{ "question": "大人気", "answers": [ "だいにんき", "おとなげ" ], "comment": "great popularity; high favour\nadultness; maturity" },
	{ "question": "大会", "answers": [ "たいかい" ], "comment": "convention; tournament; mass meeting; rally" },
	{ "question": "大力", "answers": [ "だいりき" ], "comment": "immense physical strength" },
	{ "question": "大口", "answers": [ "おおぐち", "おおくち" ], "comment": "big mouth\nboastful speech; tall talk\nlarge amount; large sum" },
	{ "question": "大名", "answers": [ "だいみょう" ], "comment": "daimyo (Japanese feudal lord); daimio" },
	{ "question": "大学", "answers": [ "だいがく" ], "comment": "post-secondary education institution, incl. university, college, etc.\nformer central university of Kyoto (established under the ritsuryo system for the training of government administrators)\nthe Great Learning (one of the Four Books)" },
	{ "question": "大学生", "answers": [ "だいがくせい" ], "comment": "university student; college student" },
	{ "question": "大小", "answers": [ "だいしょう" ], "comment": "sizes (various); large and small\ndaisho (matched pair of long and short swords)\nlarge and small drums\nlong months and short months\nsic bo (Macau dice game); tai sai; dai siu; big and small" },
	{ "question": "大山", "answers": [ "たいざん", "おおやま" ], "comment": "great mountain" },
	{ "question": "大川", "answers": [ "おおかわ" ], "comment": "big river" },
	{ "question": "大手", "answers": [ "おおて", "おおで" ], "comment": "major company; big company\nfront castle gate\nforce attacking the front of a castle\nfull length of one's arm (from shoulder to fingertip)" },
	{ "question": "大木", "answers": [ "たいぼく" ], "comment": "large tree" },
	{ "question": "大本", "answers": [ "おおもと", "たいほん" ], "comment": "foundation; basic principles\nroot; source; origin; cause" },
	{ "question": "大根", "answers": [ "だいこん" ], "comment": "daikon (variety of large white Oriental radish, Raphanus sativus var. longipinnatus)\nham actor\nroot; source; origin; basis" },
	{ "question": "大正", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "Taisho era (1912.7.30-1926.12.25)" },
	{ "question": "大気", "answers": [ "たいき" ], "comment": "atmosphere" },
	{ "question": "大男", "answers": [ "おおおとこ" ], "comment": "great man; giant" },
	{ "question": "大目", "answers": [ "おおめ" ], "comment": "magnanimity; tolerance\nlarge eyes" },
	{ "question": "大空", "answers": [ "おおぞら", "たいくう" ], "comment": "heavens; firmament; sky" },
	{ "question": "大臣", "answers": [ "だいじん" ], "comment": "cabinet minister\nminister (of government); noble\nnobleman's residence" },
	{ "question": "大金", "answers": [ "たいきん", "おおがね" ], "comment": "large amount of money; great cost" },
	{ "question": "大雨", "answers": [ "おおあめ", "たいう" ], "comment": "heavy rain" },
	{ "question": "天", "answers": [ "てん", "あま", "あめ" ], "comment": "sky\nheaven\nsvarga (heaven-like realm visited as a stage of death and rebirth)\ndeva (divine being of Buddhism)" },
	{ "question": "天上", "answers": [ "てんじょう" ], "comment": "the heavens" },
	{ "question": "天下", "answers": [ "てんか", "てんげ" ], "comment": "the whole world\nthe whole country\nsociety; the public\nsupremacy over a nation; government of a country; the ruling power\nhaving one's own way; doing as one pleases\npeerless; incomparable; superlative; world-famous\nshogun (Edo period)" },
	{ "question": "天下る", "answers": [ "あまくだる" ], "comment": "to descend from heaven" },
	{ "question": "天下一", "answers": [ "てんかいち" ], "comment": "unique thing; best on earth" },
	{ "question": "天子", "answers": [ "てんし" ], "comment": "emperor; ruler (with a heavenly mandate)\nheavenly being; celestial being" },
	{ "question": "天才", "answers": [ "てんさい" ], "comment": "genius; prodigy; natural gift" },
	{ "question": "天日", "answers": [ "てんぴ", "てんじつ" ], "comment": "the sun; sunlight" },
	{ "question": "天気", "answers": [ "てんき" ], "comment": "weather; the elements\nfair weather; fine weather" },
	{ "question": "天水", "answers": [ "てんすい" ], "comment": "rain water" },
	{ "question": "天火", "answers": [ "てんぴ" ], "comment": "fire caused by lightning\noven; (waffle) iron" },
	{ "question": "天空", "answers": [ "てんくう" ], "comment": "sky; air; ether; firmament; the heavens" },
	{ "question": "太る", "answers": [ "ふとる" ], "comment": "to grow fat (stout, plump); to become fat; to gain weight" },
	{ "question": "失敗", "answers": [ "しっぱい" ], "comment": "failure; mistake; blunder" },
	{ "question": "失笑", "answers": [ "しっしょう" ], "comment": "laughing at an inappropriate time; not being able to hold back one's laughter\nscornful laughter; snicker; snigger" },
	{ "question": "女", "answers": [ "おんな", "め" ], "comment": "female; woman; female sex\nfemale lover; girlfriend; mistress; (someone's) woman\nwoman; girl; daughter\nChinese \"Girl\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\nfemale; woman\nwife" },
	{ "question": "女子", "answers": [ "じょし", "おなご" ], "comment": "woman; girl\nvagina\ngirl" },
	{ "question": "女学校", "answers": [ "じょがっこう" ], "comment": "girl's school" },
	{ "question": "女学生", "answers": [ "じょがくせい" ], "comment": "schoolgirl" },
	{ "question": "女手", "answers": [ "おんなで" ], "comment": "female help; female labor; female labour\nwoman's handwriting\nhiragana" },
	{ "question": "女王", "answers": [ "じょおう" ], "comment": "queen" },
	{ "question": "妹", "answers": [ "いもうと" ], "comment": "younger sister\ndarling (only of a woman); dear; honey; my betrothed\none's sister\nfriend" },
	{ "question": "姉", "answers": [ "あね" ], "comment": "older sister; elder sister\nhonorific suffix used after the name of a woman of equal or higher status\nused after the name of someone who is an older sister figure\nused with various honorifics to mean (older) sister" },
	{ "question": "婦人", "answers": [ "ふじん" ], "comment": "woman; lady; adult female" },
	{ "question": "子", "answers": [ "こ" ], "comment": "child\nyoung (animal)\nyoung woman; young geisha\noffshoot\ninterest\nnew shares\nplayer who is not a dealer (in cards, mahjong, etc.)\nbird egg\n-er (often of young women)\nfirst sign of Chinese zodiac (The Rat, 11pm-1am, north, November)\nfruit; nut\nseed\n(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.\ncontent; substance\nchild (esp. a boy)\nviscount\nmaster (founder of a school of thought, esp. Confucius)\nphilosophy (branch of Chinese literature); non-Confucian Hundred Schools of Thought writings\nyou (of one's equals)\n-er (i.e. a man who spends all his time doing...)\nhonorific (or familiar) suffix used after a name\nchild\ninterest" },
	{ "question": "子犬", "answers": [ "こいぬ" ], "comment": "puppy" },
	{ "question": "字", "answers": [ "じ", "あざ" ], "comment": "section of village\ncharacter (i.e. kanji)\nhand-writing; penmanship\nthe ... word (i.e. \"the L word\" = \"love\")\nChinese courtesy name (name formerly given to adult Chinese men, used in place of their given name in formal situations)\nnickname\nsection of a village" },
	{ "question": "字下げ", "answers": [ "じさげ" ], "comment": "indentation" },
	{ "question": "存在", "answers": [ "そんざい" ], "comment": "existence; being" },
	{ "question": "季節", "answers": [ "きせつ" ], "comment": "season" },
	{ "question": "学", "answers": [ "がく" ], "comment": "-ology; -ics; study of ...\nlearning; scholarship; erudition; knowledge" },
	{ "question": "学ぶ", "answers": [ "まなぶ" ], "comment": "to study (in depth); to learn; to take lessons in" },
	{ "question": "学力", "answers": [ "がくりょく" ], "comment": "scholarly ability; scholarship; knowledge; literary ability" },
	{ "question": "学名", "answers": [ "がくめい" ], "comment": "technical name (often the internationally accepted Latin, scientific, or Linnaean name of plants and animals)" },
	{ "question": "学園", "answers": [ "がくえん" ], "comment": "educational institution; school; academy; campus" },
	{ "question": "学年", "answers": [ "がくねん" ], "comment": "academic year; school year\nyear in school; grade in school" },
	{ "question": "学校", "answers": [ "がっこう" ], "comment": "school" },
	{ "question": "孫", "answers": [ "まご" ], "comment": "grandchild" },
	{ "question": "守る", "answers": [ "まもる" ], "comment": "to protect; to guard; to defend\nto keep (i.e. a promise); to abide (by the rules); to observe; to obey; to follow" },
	{ "question": "安心", "answers": [ "あんしん" ], "comment": "relief; peace of mind\nobtaining peace of mind through faith or ascetic practice" },
	{ "question": "安静", "answers": [ "あんせい" ], "comment": "rest; quiet; repose" },
	{ "question": "完全", "answers": [ "かんぜん" ], "comment": "perfection; completeness" },
	{ "question": "家事", "answers": [ "かじ" ], "comment": "housework; domestic chores\nfamily affairs; household matters" },
	{ "question": "家族", "answers": [ "かぞく" ], "comment": "family; members of a family" },
	{ "question": "宿題", "answers": [ "しゅくだい" ], "comment": "homework" },
	{ "question": "寄る", "answers": [ "よる" ], "comment": "to approach; to draw near; to come near; to be close to\nto gather (in one place); to come together; to meet\nto stop by (while on one's way to another place); to drop by; to make a short visit\nto grow old; to grow high (number, etc.)\nto grow (wrinkly)\nto lean against; to recline on\nto push one's opponent while holding their belt\nto decide on a price and come to a deal\nto be swayed by (a person); to yield to" },
	{ "question": "小", "answers": [ "しょう" ], "comment": "smallness; small item\nshort month (i.e. having fewer than 31 days)\nelementary school\nyounger or inferior (of two items or people with the same name)\nunit of field area (approx. 400 sq m)\nsmall; little; slight\nslightly less than; just about\nsomewhat; somehow\nminor (sometimes derogatory); petty\nsmall; narrow\nfamiliar prefix\nslightly; a bit\nsmall; little\nsmall; little; dear (figurative sense)\nnarrow; thin" },
	{ "question": "小さい", "answers": [ "ちいさい" ], "comment": "small; little; tiny" },
	{ "question": "小さな", "answers": [ "ちいさな" ], "comment": "small; little; tiny" },
	{ "question": "小人", "answers": [ "こびと", "しょうじん", "しょうにん" ], "comment": "child; small person\ndwarf; midget\nnarrow-minded person; mean person" },
	{ "question": "小力", "answers": [ "こぢから" ] },
	{ "question": "小口", "answers": [ "こぐち" ], "comment": "cut end; edge (of a page, etc.)\nsmall amount; small sum\nbeginning; clue\ntiger's den; jaws of death; dangerous place" },
	{ "question": "小学校", "answers": [ "しょうがっこう" ], "comment": "primary school; elementary school; grade school" },
	{ "question": "小学生", "answers": [ "しょうがくせい" ], "comment": "elementary school student; primary school student; grade school student" },
	{ "question": "小川", "answers": [ "おがわ" ], "comment": "streamlet; brook" },
	{ "question": "小文", "answers": [ "しょうぶん" ] },
	{ "question": "小男", "answers": [ "こおとこ" ], "comment": "small man" },
	{ "question": "小石", "answers": [ "こいし" ], "comment": "pebble" },
	{ "question": "小耳", "answers": [ "こみみ" ], "comment": "overhear; happened to hear that" },
	{ "question": "小金", "answers": [ "こがね" ], "comment": "small sum of money" },
	{ "question": "小雨", "answers": [ "こさめ", "しょうう", "こあめ" ], "comment": "light rain; drizzle" },
	{ "question": "少し", "answers": [ "すこし" ], "comment": "small quantity; little; few; something\nlittle while\nshort distance" },
	{ "question": "屋根", "answers": [ "やね" ], "comment": "roof" },
	{ "question": "山", "answers": [ "やま" ], "comment": "mountain; hill\nmine (e.g. coal mine)\nheap; pile\ncrown (of a hat); thread (of a screw); tread (of a tire); protruding part of an object\nclimax; peak; critical point\nguess; speculation\ncriminal case; crime\nmountain climbing; mountaineering\nfestival float (esp. one mounted with a decorative halberd)\nwall; wall tile\ntemple; temple grounds\nwild\nMt.; Mount\nMt.; Mount\nmountain; hill" },
	{ "question": "山々", "answers": [ "やまやま" ], "comment": "(many) mountains\nvery much (esp. wanting to do something one cannot); greatly; really" },
	{ "question": "山下", "answers": [ "やました", "さんか", "やまもと" ], "comment": "foot of a mountain; base of a mountain\nmine; colliery\nowner of a mountain; operator of a mine\nfoot of a mountain; base of a mountain" },
	{ "question": "山中", "answers": [ "やまなか", "さんちゅう" ], "comment": "in the mountains; among the mountains" },
	{ "question": "山川", "answers": [ "やまがわ", "さんせん" ], "comment": "mountains and rivers\nmountain rivers" },
	{ "question": "山村", "answers": [ "さんそん" ], "comment": "mountain village" },
	{ "question": "山林", "answers": [ "さんりん" ], "comment": "mountain forest; forest on a mountain; montane forest\nmountains and forest" },
	{ "question": "山水", "answers": [ "さんすい", "やまみず" ], "comment": "mountain and water; landscape (containing hills and rivers)\nlandscape picture\nmountain stream; water that flows down from a mountain\ngarden which contains an artificial hill and a pond" },
	{ "question": "山田", "answers": [ "やまだ" ] },
	{ "question": "山脈", "answers": [ "さんみゃく" ], "comment": "mountain range" },
	{ "question": "岩", "answers": [ "いわ" ], "comment": "rock; boulder\ncrag; cliff\nanchor" },
	{ "question": "島", "answers": [ "しま" ], "comment": "island\nterritory (of a prostitute, organized crime gang, etc.); turf\nIsland\ninsula; island; islet" },
	{ "question": "川", "answers": [ "かわ" ], "comment": "river; stream\nthe .... river; (suffix used with the names of rivers)" },
	{ "question": "川の字", "answers": [ "かわのじ" ] },
	{ "question": "川上", "answers": [ "かわかみ" ], "comment": "upper reaches of a river; upstream" },
	{ "question": "川下", "answers": [ "かわしも" ], "comment": "downstream" },
	{ "question": "川下り", "answers": [ "かわくだり" ], "comment": "going downstream (in a boat)" },
	{ "question": "川水", "answers": [ "かわみず" ] },
	{ "question": "巣", "answers": [ "す" ], "comment": "nest; rookery; breeding place; hive\nden\nhaunt\n(spider's) web" },
	{ "question": "工事", "answers": [ "こうじ" ], "comment": "construction work; construction; work (related to construction, e.g. painting, concrete-pouring, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "工業", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "(manufacturing) industry" },
	{ "question": "左", "answers": [ "ひだり" ], "comment": "left; left hand side\nleft (esp. in vertical Japanese writing); the following" },
	{ "question": "左右", "answers": [ "さゆう" ], "comment": "left and right\ninfluence; control; domination\n(doing) various things; (doing) this and that\nbeing apt to; being prone to; tending to become\nsomehow or other; anyhow; anyway" },
	{ "question": "左手", "answers": [ "ひだりて", "ゆんで" ], "comment": "left hand\nleft-hand side; left-hand direction; (on) the left\none's left hand; bow hand" },
	{ "question": "左足", "answers": [ "ひだりあし" ], "comment": "left foot" },
	{ "question": "差", "answers": [ "さ" ], "comment": "difference; variation\ndifference\nbetween (e.g. two people); face to face\nhindrance; impediment\narrhythmic section of recitative in noh music\nprefix used for stress or emphasis\ncounter for traditional dance songs" },
	{ "question": "市長", "answers": [ "しちょう" ], "comment": "mayor" },
	{ "question": "布", "answers": [ "ぬの" ], "comment": "cloth\nbujian (spade-shaped bronze coin of ancient China)\nunit of measurement for cloth breadth (30-38 cm)" },
	{ "question": "希望", "answers": [ "きぼう" ], "comment": "hope; wish; aspiration" },
	{ "question": "帰る", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to return; to come home; to go home; to go back\nto leave\nto get home; to get to home plate" },
	{ "question": "常温", "answers": [ "じょうおん" ], "comment": "normal temperature; average temperature; fixed temperature" },
	{ "question": "平等", "answers": [ "びょうどう" ], "comment": "equality; impartiality; evenness" },
	{ "question": "年", "answers": [ "とし", "ねん" ], "comment": "year\nage; years\npast one's prime; old age\nyear (e.g. AD)\ncounter for years\ncounter for years (following a number in the hito-futa-mi counting system)" },
	{ "question": "幸福", "answers": [ "こうふく" ], "comment": "happiness; blessedness; joy; well-being" },
	{ "question": "幼虫", "answers": [ "ようちゅう" ], "comment": "larva; grub; maggot" },
	{ "question": "広い", "answers": [ "ひろい" ], "comment": "spacious; vast; wide" },
	{ "question": "庭園", "answers": [ "ていえん" ], "comment": "garden; park" },
	{ "question": "建築", "answers": [ "けんちく" ], "comment": "construction; architecture (of buildings)" },
	{ "question": "弁当", "answers": [ "べんとう" ], "comment": "bento; Japanese box lunch" },
	{ "question": "弁解", "answers": [ "べんかい" ], "comment": "explanation (e.g. for one's actions); excuse; justification; defense; defence" },
	{ "question": "弓", "answers": [ "ゆみ" ], "comment": "bow (and arrow)\narchery\nbow (for a violin, etc.)\nbow (and arrow)\nunit of distance to an archery target (approx. six feet)\nunit of distance for land surveying (approx. eight feet)\nbow (and arrow; esp. of a noble)" },
	{ "question": "引く", "answers": [ "ひく" ], "comment": "to pull\nto draw (attention, etc.); to attract (interest, etc.)\nto draw back\nto draw (card, mahjong tile, etc.)\nto draw (plan, line, etc.)\nto catch (cold)\nto play (string instr.)\nto look up (e.g. dictionary); to consult\nto haul; to pull (vehicles)\nto subtract\nto ebb; to fade\nto descend (from); to inherit (a characteristic)\nto quote; to raise (as evidence)\nto lay (a cable); to draw (a cable)" },
	{ "question": "弱点", "answers": [ "じゃくてん" ], "comment": "weak point; weakness; shortcoming; defect; flaw; sore spot; tender spot" },
	{ "question": "強力", "answers": [ "きょうりょく" ], "comment": "powerful; strong\nherculean strength; mountain carrier-guide" },
	{ "question": "当日", "answers": [ "とうじつ" ], "comment": "appointed day; very day" },
	{ "question": "復習", "answers": [ "ふくしゅう" ], "comment": "review; revision" },
	{ "question": "必然", "answers": [ "ひつぜん" ], "comment": "inevitable; necessary; certain; sure\ninevitability; necessity" },
	{ "question": "必要", "answers": [ "ひつよう" ], "comment": "necessary; needed; essential; indispensable\nnecessity; need; requirement" },
	{ "question": "志願", "answers": [ "しがん" ], "comment": "aspiration; volunteering; desire; application" },
	{ "question": "快速", "answers": [ "かいそく" ], "comment": "high speed; rapidity\nrapid-service train (not as fast as express); rapid train" },
	{ "question": "急ぐ", "answers": [ "いそぐ" ], "comment": "to hurry; to rush; to hasten; to make something happen sooner" },
	{ "question": "息", "answers": [ "いき" ], "comment": "breath; breathing\ntone; mood\nson\npenis" },
	{ "question": "悲しい", "answers": [ "かなしい" ], "comment": "sad; sorrowful" },
	{ "question": "意識", "answers": [ "いしき" ], "comment": "consciousness\nawareness; sense\nmano-vijnana (mental consciousness, cognizer of sensory information)" },
	{ "question": "感想", "answers": [ "かんそう" ], "comment": "impressions; thoughts" },
	{ "question": "態度", "answers": [ "たいど" ], "comment": "attitude; manner; behaviour" },
	{ "question": "成功", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "success; hit" },
	{ "question": "戸", "answers": [ "と" ], "comment": "door (esp. Japanese-style)\nshutter; window shutter\nentrance (to a home)\nnarrows\ncounter for houses, households, apartments, etc." },
	{ "question": "所属", "answers": [ "しょぞく" ], "comment": "attached to; belong to; member; affiliation" },
	{ "question": "手", "answers": [ "て" ], "comment": "hand; arm\nforepaw; foreleg\nhandle\nhand; worker; help\ntrouble; care; effort\nmeans; way; trick; move; technique; workmanship\nhand; handwriting\nkind; type; sort\none's hands; one's possession\nability to cope\nhand (of cards)\ndirection\nmove (in go, shogi, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "手下", "answers": [ "てした" ], "comment": "subordinate; underling; henchman; minion" },
	{ "question": "手中", "answers": [ "しゅちゅう" ], "comment": "in one's hands; in one's control" },
	{ "question": "手先", "answers": [ "てさき" ], "comment": "fingers\nunderling; stooge; subordinate; pawn" },
	{ "question": "手入れ", "answers": [ "ていれ" ], "comment": "care; looking after; repair; maintenance; tending; trimming; grooming\n(police) raid; crackdown" },
	{ "question": "手口", "answers": [ "てぐち" ], "comment": "modus operandi; criminal technique; trick" },
	{ "question": "手帳", "answers": [ "てちょう" ], "comment": "notebook; memo pad; (pocket) diary\ncertificate\nidentification card" },
	{ "question": "手本", "answers": [ "てほん" ], "comment": "copybook\nmodel; pattern" },
	{ "question": "手水", "answers": [ "てみず", "ちょうず" ], "comment": "water for washing or moistening one's hands" },
	{ "question": "手玉", "answers": [ "てだま" ], "comment": "beanbags; jackstones; cueball" },
	{ "question": "手紙", "answers": [ "てがみ" ], "comment": "letter" },
	{ "question": "手術", "answers": [ "しゅじゅつ" ], "comment": "(surgical) operation; procedure" },
	{ "question": "手足", "answers": [ "てあし", "しゅそく" ], "comment": "hands and feet; limbs" },
	{ "question": "打席", "answers": [ "だせき" ], "comment": "batter's box; one's turn at bat" },
	{ "question": "技術", "answers": [ "ぎじゅつ" ], "comment": "technology; engineering\ntechnique; skill\nart; craft" },
	{ "question": "投げる", "answers": [ "なげる" ], "comment": "to throw; to cast away\nto face defeat; to give up" },
	{ "question": "投球", "answers": [ "とうきゅう" ], "comment": "pitching; throwing a ball; bowling (in cricket); pitched ball" },
	{ "question": "招待", "answers": [ "しょうたい" ], "comment": "invitation" },
	{ "question": "指", "answers": [ "ゆび" ], "comment": "finger; toe; digit\nbetween (e.g. two people); face to face\nhindrance; impediment\narrhythmic section of recitative in noh music\nprefix used for stress or emphasis\ncounter for traditional dance songs" },
	{ "question": "採取", "answers": [ "さいしゅ" ], "comment": "picking; collecting; harvesting" },
	{ "question": "提言", "answers": [ "ていげん" ], "comment": "proposal; motion; recommendation" },
	{ "question": "損失", "answers": [ "そんしつ" ], "comment": "loss (e.g. assets or profits)" },
	{ "question": "改札", "answers": [ "かいさつ" ], "comment": "examination of tickets\nticket gate; ticket barrier" },
	{ "question": "敗れる", "answers": [ "やぶれる" ], "comment": "to be defeated; to be beaten; to be unsuccessful; to lose" },
	{ "question": "教える", "answers": [ "おしえる" ], "comment": "to teach; to instruct\nto tell; to inform\nto preach" },
	{ "question": "教室", "answers": [ "きょうしつ" ], "comment": "classroom\ndepartment; laboratory\nsingle-room school; small school" },
	{ "question": "教授", "answers": [ "きょうじゅ" ], "comment": "professor\nteaching; instruction" },
	{ "question": "散歩", "answers": [ "さんぽ" ], "comment": "walk; stroll" },
	{ "question": "整理", "answers": [ "せいり" ], "comment": "sorting; arrangement; organization; putting in order; adjustment; regulation\nliquidation; settlement; consolidation; clearance (e.g. debt); paying off\nretrenchment; curtailment; cutting down; disposal" },
	{ "question": "文", "answers": [ "ふみ", "ぶん", "もん", "あや" ], "comment": "letter; writings\nsentence\ncomposition; text; writings\nthe literary arts (as opposed to the military arts); academia; literature\nfigure; design\nstyle (of writing); figure (of speech)\ndesign; plot; plan\nminor market fluctuation; technical correction\ncat's cradle\nlease rod (in a loom)\none-thousandth of a kan (obsolete unit of currency)\n2.4 cm (traditional unit used to measure shoe sizes)\nletter; character; sentence\nscripture; incantation" },
	{ "question": "文人", "answers": [ "ぶんじん" ], "comment": "person of letters; literary person\nperson of letters; poet" },
	{ "question": "文名", "answers": [ "ぶんめい" ], "comment": "literary fame" },
	{ "question": "文字", "answers": [ "もじ", "もんじ" ], "comment": "letter (of alphabet); character\nliteral" },
	{ "question": "文学", "answers": [ "ぶんがく" ], "comment": "literature" },
	{ "question": "文目", "answers": [ "あやめ" ], "comment": "pattern; design; distinction" },
	{ "question": "料理", "answers": [ "りょうり" ], "comment": "cooking; cookery; cuisine\ndealing with something; handling; administration; management" },
	{ "question": "新しい", "answers": [ "あたらしい" ], "comment": "new; novel; fresh; recent; latest; up-to-date; modern" },
	{ "question": "新聞", "answers": [ "しんぶん" ], "comment": "newspaper" },
	{ "question": "方法", "answers": [ "ほうほう" ], "comment": "method; process; manner; way; means; technique" },
	{ "question": "旗", "answers": [ "はた" ], "comment": "flag" },
	{ "question": "日", "answers": [ "ひ" ], "comment": "day; days\nsun; sunshine; sunlight\ncase (esp. unfortunate); event\nSunday\nday (of the month)\ncounter for days\nJapan\nday of month\ncounter for days" },
	{ "question": "日々", "answers": [ "ひび", "にちにち" ], "comment": "every day; daily; day after day; days (e.g. good old days)" },
	{ "question": "日の本", "answers": [ "ひのもと" ], "comment": "Japan" },
	{ "question": "日本", "answers": [ "にほん", "にっぽん" ], "comment": "Japan" },
	{ "question": "旧友", "answers": [ "きゅうゆう" ], "comment": "crony; old friend" },
	{ "question": "早", "answers": [ "はや" ], "comment": "already; now; by this time\nearly" },
	{ "question": "早々と", "answers": [ "はやばやと" ], "comment": "early; quickly; promptly​" },
	{ "question": "早々に", "answers": [ "そうそうに" ], "comment": "as soon as...; just after...; immediately after...​\nhurriedly; in haste; quickly; promptly; early" },
	{ "question": "早い", "answers": [ "はやい" ], "comment": "fast; quick; hasty; brisk\nearly (in the day, etc.); premature\n(too) soon; not yet; (too) early\neasy; simple; quick" },
	{ "question": "早まる", "answers": [ "はやまる" ], "comment": "to move ahead (three hours, etc.); to move up\nto quicken; to speed up; to gather speed\nto be hasty; to be rash" },
	{ "question": "早める", "answers": [ "はやめる" ], "comment": "to hasten; to quicken; to expedite; to precipitate; to accelerate" },
	{ "question": "早出", "answers": [ "はやで" ], "comment": "early arrival" },
	{ "question": "早口", "answers": [ "はやくち", "はやぐち" ], "comment": "fast-talking; rapid talking" },
	{ "question": "早年", "answers": [ "そうねん" ] },
	{ "question": "早耳", "answers": [ "はやみみ" ], "comment": "insider; keen of hearing; quick-eared; sharp-eared" },
	{ "question": "早足", "answers": [ "はやあし" ], "comment": "quick pace; quick steps; quick march\ntrot (horse gait)" },
	{ "question": "昔話", "answers": [ "むかしばなし" ], "comment": "old tale; folk tale; legend\nreminiscence" },
	{ "question": "星", "answers": [ "ほし" ], "comment": "star; any light-emitting (or reflecting) heavenly body (except for the sun and the moon)\noffender; perpetrator\nstar point (in go); hoshi; intersection marked with a dot\ncircular symbol (said to be shaped like a shining star)\nbullseye\none's star (out of the nine stars); the star that determines one's fate\nsmall dot; spot\npoint; score\nChinese \"star\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\nSingapore" },
	{ "question": "昭和", "answers": [ "しょうわ" ], "comment": "Showa era (1926.12.25-1989.1.7)" },
	{ "question": "時間", "answers": [ "じかん" ], "comment": "time\nhours (period of)" },
	{ "question": "暑い", "answers": [ "あつい" ], "comment": "hot (weather, etc.); warm" },
	{ "question": "暗い", "answers": [ "くらい" ], "comment": "dark; gloomy\ndark (in colour); dull\ndepressed; dispirited\nsorrowful; bitter (as in a dark past)\nunclear; unfamiliar; unknown" },
	{ "question": "暴動", "answers": [ "ぼうどう" ], "comment": "insurrection; rebellion; revolt; riot; uprising" },
	{ "question": "曲がる", "answers": [ "まがる" ], "comment": "to bend; to curve; to warp; to wind; to twist\nto turn\nto be awry; to be askew; to be crooked" },
	{ "question": "最寄", "answers": [ "もより" ], "comment": "nearest; neighbouring; neighboring; nearby" },
	{ "question": "月", "answers": [ "つき" ], "comment": "moon\nmonth\nmonth (of the year); used after number or question word (e.g. nan or nani)\nMonday" },
	{ "question": "月曜", "answers": [ "げつよう" ], "comment": "Monday" },
	{ "question": "月見", "answers": [ "つきみ" ], "comment": "viewing the moon" },
	{ "question": "有害", "answers": [ "ゆうがい" ], "comment": "harmful; hazardous" },
	{ "question": "有終", "answers": [ "ゆうしゅう" ], "comment": "perfection" },
	{ "question": "朝", "answers": [ "あさ" ], "comment": "morning\ndynasty\nreign\nperiod; epoch; age\ncourt\nNorth Korea" },
	{ "question": "木", "answers": [ "き" ], "comment": "tree; shrub; bush\nwood; timber\nThursday\nwood (first of the five elements)" },
	{ "question": "木目", "answers": [ "きめ", "もくめ" ], "comment": "texture (e.g. skin, fabric)\ngrain (e.g. wood)\ndetail\ngrain (of wood); curly grain" },
	{ "question": "木石", "answers": [ "ぼくせき" ], "comment": "trees and stones\nunfeeling person" },
	{ "question": "本", "answers": [ "ほん", "もと" ], "comment": "origin; source\nbase; basis; foundation; root\ncause\ningredient; material\noriginal cost (or capital, principal, etc.)\n(plant) root; (tree) trunk\nfirst section of a waka\ncounter for blades of grass, tree trunks, etc., and for falcons (in falconry)\nhandle (chopsticks, brush, etc.); grip\nbook; volume; script\nthis; present\nmain; head\nreal; regular\ncounter for long cylindrical things; counter for films, TV shows, etc.; counter for goals, home runs, etc.; counter for telephone calls" },
	{ "question": "本の虫", "answers": [ "ほんのむし" ], "comment": "bookworm; bibliophile; bibliophage" },
	{ "question": "本人", "answers": [ "ほんにん" ], "comment": "the person himself" },
	{ "question": "本名", "answers": [ "ほんみょう", "ほんめい" ], "comment": "real name" },
	{ "question": "本土", "answers": [ "ほんど" ], "comment": "mainland; one's home country; the country proper" },
	{ "question": "本学", "answers": [ "ほんがく" ], "comment": "this university; this educational establishment" },
	{ "question": "本山", "answers": [ "ほんざん" ], "comment": "head temple; this temple" },
	{ "question": "本年", "answers": [ "ほんねん" ], "comment": "this (current) year" },
	{ "question": "本手", "answers": [ "ほんて" ], "comment": "one's true ability; the right way; professional" },
	{ "question": "本文", "answers": [ "ほんぶん", "ほんもん" ], "comment": "text (of document); body (of letter)" },
	{ "question": "本日", "answers": [ "ほんじつ" ], "comment": "today" },
	{ "question": "本月", "answers": [ "ほんげつ" ], "comment": "this month" },
	{ "question": "本校", "answers": [ "ほんこう" ], "comment": "main school; this school" },
	{ "question": "本気", "answers": [ "ほんき" ], "comment": "seriousness; earnestness; truth; sanctity" },
	{ "question": "本田", "answers": [ "ほんでん" ], "comment": "rice paddy" },
	{ "question": "本草", "answers": [ "ほんぞう" ], "comment": "plants; medicinal herbs" },
	{ "question": "本音", "answers": [ "ほんね" ], "comment": "real intention; motive; true opinion; what one really thinks" },
	{ "question": "材料", "answers": [ "ざいりょう" ], "comment": "ingredients; material\nmaterial (for a novel, experiment, etc.); subject matter; data\nbasis (for a decision); grounds; evidence\n(market) factor" },
	{ "question": "村", "answers": [ "むら" ], "comment": "village" },
	{ "question": "村雨", "answers": [ "むらさめ" ], "comment": "passing shower" },
	{ "question": "条件", "answers": [ "じょうけん" ], "comment": "condition; conditions; term; terms; requirement; requirements" },
	{ "question": "条約", "answers": [ "じょうやく" ], "comment": "treaty; pact" },
	{ "question": "東京", "answers": [ "とうきょう" ], "comment": "Tokyo" },
	{ "question": "松", "answers": [ "まつ" ], "comment": "pine tree (Pinus spp.)\nhighest (of a three-tier ranking system)" },
	{ "question": "板", "answers": [ "いた" ], "comment": "board; plank\nsheet (of metal); plate (of glass); pane; slab\ncutting board; chopping board\nchef (esp. of high-end Japanese cuisine); cook\nstage (i.e. at a theatre)" },
	{ "question": "林", "answers": [ "はやし" ], "comment": "woods; forest; copse; thicket\nbunch; line (of something); collection" },
	{ "question": "林学", "answers": [ "りんがく" ], "comment": "forestry" },
	{ "question": "林立", "answers": [ "りんりつ" ], "comment": "standing close together; bristling (with)" },
	{ "question": "査定", "answers": [ "さてい" ], "comment": "assessment; investigation; audit; revision" },
	{ "question": "栄養", "answers": [ "えいよう" ], "comment": "nutrition; nourishment" },
	{ "question": "校門", "answers": [ "こうもん" ], "comment": "school gate" },
	{ "question": "格別", "answers": [ "かくべつ" ], "comment": "particular; special; exceptional; especial\nparticularly; especially; exceptionally" },
	{ "question": "案外", "answers": [ "あんがい" ], "comment": "unexpectedly; surprisingly\nunexpected; unanticipated; unforeseen; surprising" },
	{ "question": "森", "answers": [ "もり" ], "comment": "forest\nshrine grove" },
	{ "question": "森林", "answers": [ "しんりん" ], "comment": "forest; woods" },
	{ "question": "植物", "answers": [ "しょくぶつ" ], "comment": "plant; vegetation" },
	{ "question": "検出", "answers": [ "けんしゅつ" ], "comment": "detection; sense (e.g. sensor)" },
	{ "question": "楽しい", "answers": [ "たのしい" ], "comment": "enjoyable; fun" },
	{ "question": "様子", "answers": [ "ようす" ], "comment": "state; state of affairs; situation; circumstances\nappearance; look; aspect\nsign; indication" },
	{ "question": "標識", "answers": [ "ひょうしき" ], "comment": "sign; mark; flag" },
	{ "question": "橋", "answers": [ "はし" ], "comment": "bridge\npons (pontes); pons Varolii; pontine; part of the brain stem (links the medulla oblongata and cerebellum with the midbrain)" },
	{ "question": "機会", "answers": [ "きかい" ], "comment": "chance; opportunity" },
	{ "question": "機械", "answers": [ "きかい" ], "comment": "machine; mechanism\ninstrument; appliance; apparatus" },
	{ "question": "欠席", "answers": [ "けっせき" ], "comment": "absence; non-attendance" },
	{ "question": "次第", "answers": [ "しだい" ], "comment": "depending on\nas soon as; immediately (upon)\nin accordance with\norder; program; programme; precedence\ncircumstances; course of events; reason" },
	{ "question": "歌", "answers": [ "うた" ], "comment": "song\nclassical Japanese poetry (esp. tanka)\nmodern poetry" },
	{ "question": "止まる", "answers": [ "とまる", "とどまる" ], "comment": "to stop (moving); to come to a stop\nto stop (doing, working, being supplied); to come to a halt; to cease; to be stopped; to be suspended\nto alight; to perch on\nto remain; to abide; to stay (in the one place)\nto be limited to; to be confined to\nto cease; to stop; to be over" },
	{ "question": "正", "answers": [ "せい", "まさ" ], "comment": "(logical) true; regular\n10^40; ten thousand undecillion\noriginal\npositive; greater than zero\ngreater (of equal court ranks); upper; senior\ndirector (highest of the four administrative positions of the ritsuryo period); chief\nexactly; precisely\nexact; precise" },
	{ "question": "正しい", "answers": [ "ただしい" ], "comment": "right; correct\nproper; righteous; just; honest; truthful; lawful" },
	{ "question": "正す", "answers": [ "ただす" ], "comment": "to correct; to reform; to amend; to redress\nto adjust; to straighten\nto ascertain; to confirm; to verify; to make sure of\nto enquire of someone about something (inquire); to question" },
	{ "question": "正に", "answers": [ "まさに" ], "comment": "exactly; surely; certainly\nright then; just then; at that moment\njust (about to); on the verge (of doing or happening)\nduly; naturally" },
	{ "question": "正月", "answers": [ "しょうがつ" ], "comment": "New Year (esp. first three days)\nthe first month of the year; January" },
	{ "question": "正本", "answers": [ "せいほん", "しょうほん" ], "comment": "book of registration; text of a play\noriginal; original text; authenticated facsimile; authenticated copy" },
	{ "question": "正気", "answers": [ "しょうき", "せいき" ], "comment": "sanity; consciousness; soberness\ntrue character; true heart; true spirit" },
	{ "question": "武道", "answers": [ "ぶどう" ], "comment": "martial arts; military arts; Bushido" },
	{ "question": "歩く", "answers": [ "あるく" ], "comment": "to walk" },
	{ "question": "歩道", "answers": [ "ほどう" ], "comment": "footpath; walkway; sidewalk" },
	{ "question": "歴史", "answers": [ "れきし" ], "comment": "history" },
	{ "question": "残る", "answers": [ "のこる" ], "comment": "to remain; to be left" },
	{ "question": "毎週", "answers": [ "まいしゅう" ], "comment": "every week" },
	{ "question": "比例", "answers": [ "ひれい" ], "comment": "proportion" },
	{ "question": "氏名", "answers": [ "しめい" ], "comment": "full name; identity" },
	{ "question": "民宿", "answers": [ "みんしゅく" ], "comment": "pension; guesthouse; bed and breakfast; private home providing lodging for travelers (travellers)" },
	{ "question": "気", "answers": [ "き", "け" ], "comment": "spirit; mind; heart\nnature; disposition\nmotivation; intention\nmood; feelings\nambience; atmosphere; mood\nseeming; giving the appearance of; giving one the feeling of\n-like nature; -like disposition; -ish temperament\nsign; indication; trace; touch; feeling\nsomehow; for some reason; seeming to be" },
	{ "question": "気力", "answers": [ "きりょく" ], "comment": "willpower; energy; vitality" },
	{ "question": "気早な", "answers": [ "きばやな" ], "comment": "quick-tempered; impatient" },
	{ "question": "気温", "answers": [ "きおん" ], "comment": "atmospheric temperature" },
	{ "question": "水", "answers": [ "みず" ], "comment": "water (esp. cool, fresh water, e.g. drinking water)\nfluid (esp. in an animal tissue); liquid\nflood; floodwaters\nwater offered to wrestlers just prior to a bout\nbreak granted to wrestlers engaged in a prolonged bout\nWednesday\nshaved ice (served with flavored syrup)\nwater (fifth of the five elements)" },
	{ "question": "水どう", "answers": [ "すいどう" ] },
	{ "question": "水力", "answers": [ "すいりょく" ], "comment": "hydraulic power; water power" },
	{ "question": "水田", "answers": [ "すいでん", "みずた" ], "comment": "(water-filled) paddy field" },
	{ "question": "水虫", "answers": [ "みずむし" ], "comment": "athlete's foot\nwater boatman (esp. species Hesperocorixa distanti)\nAsellus hilgendorfi (species of aquatic sowbug)" },
	{ "question": "水足", "answers": [ "みずあし" ] },
	{ "question": "水車", "answers": [ "すいしゃ", "みずぐるま" ], "comment": "water wheel\nwater turbine; hydraulic turbine\nviolent wielding of weapons" },
	{ "question": "氷", "answers": [ "こおり" ], "comment": "ice\nshaved ice (usually served with flavored simple syrup)\nice\nhail" },
	{ "question": "永住", "answers": [ "えいじゅう" ], "comment": "permanent residence" },
	{ "question": "池", "answers": [ "いけ" ], "comment": "pond" },
	{ "question": "決勝", "answers": [ "けっしょう" ], "comment": "decision of a contest; finals (in sports)" },
	{ "question": "汽車", "answers": [ "きしゃ" ], "comment": "train (sometimes specifically a steam train)" },
	{ "question": "油性", "answers": [ "ゆせい" ], "comment": "oil-based" },
	{ "question": "法則", "answers": [ "ほうそく" ], "comment": "law; rule" },
	{ "question": "注意", "answers": [ "ちゅうい" ], "comment": "caution; being careful; attention (heed); warning; advice" },
	{ "question": "泳ぐ", "answers": [ "およぐ" ], "comment": "to swim" },
	{ "question": "洋服", "answers": [ "ようふく" ], "comment": "Western-style clothes (cf traditional Japanese clothes)" },
	{ "question": "活用", "answers": [ "かつよう" ], "comment": "practical use; application\nconjugation; declension; inflection" },
	{ "question": "浅い", "answers": [ "あさい" ], "comment": "shallow; superficial\nslight (wound); light (sleep); pale (colour); inadequate (knowledge)\nshort (time); early; young" },
	{ "question": "海", "answers": [ "うみ" ], "comment": "sea; ocean; waters" },
	{ "question": "海岸", "answers": [ "かいがん" ], "comment": "coast; beach" },
	{ "question": "海底", "answers": [ "かいてい" ], "comment": "bottom of the ocean\nundersea; submarine" },
	{ "question": "液体", "answers": [ "えきたい" ], "comment": "liquid; fluid" },
	{ "question": "混同", "answers": [ "こんどう" ], "comment": "confusion; mixing; merger" },
	{ "question": "清潔", "answers": [ "せいけつ" ], "comment": "clean; hygienic; sanitary\npure; virtuous; immaculate" },
	{ "question": "満席", "answers": [ "まんせき" ], "comment": "full house; all seats occupied; fully occupied" },
	{ "question": "準備", "answers": [ "じゅんび" ], "comment": "preparation; setup; arrangements; provision; reserve" },
	{ "question": "漁", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "fishing; gathering seafood (e.g. clams, seaweed)\ncatch (e.g. of fish); haul\nfishing; collecting shells\nfisherman" },
	{ "question": "演技", "answers": [ "えんぎ" ], "comment": "acting; performance" },
	{ "question": "火", "answers": [ "ひ" ], "comment": "fire; flame; blaze\nTuesday\nfire (second of the five elements)" },
	{ "question": "火の手", "answers": [ "ひのて" ], "comment": "flames; blaze; fire" },
	{ "question": "火力", "answers": [ "かりょく" ], "comment": "heating power; thermal power\nfirepower" },
	{ "question": "火口", "answers": [ "かこう", "ひぐち", "ほくち" ], "comment": "crater; caldera\nburner (e.g. on a furnace)\nburner; nozzle; origin of a fire\ntinder; touchwood; charcloth" },
	{ "question": "火山", "answers": [ "かざん" ], "comment": "volcano" },
	{ "question": "火花", "answers": [ "ひばな" ], "comment": "spark" },
	{ "question": "点数", "answers": [ "てんすう" ], "comment": "marks; points; score; runs; number of items; credits" },
	{ "question": "無理", "answers": [ "むり" ], "comment": "unreasonable; unnatural; unjustifiable\nimpossible\nforcible; forced; compulsory\nexcessive (work, etc.); immoderate\nto work too hard; to try too hard\nirrational" },
	{ "question": "熱湯", "answers": [ "ねっとう" ], "comment": "boiling water\nwarmer than usual bath" },
	{ "question": "牛肉", "answers": [ "ぎゅうにく" ], "comment": "beef" },
	{ "question": "特別", "answers": [ "とくべつ" ], "comment": "special" },
	{ "question": "犬", "answers": [ "いぬ" ], "comment": "dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)\nsnoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)\nloser; asshole\ncounterfeit; inferior; useless; wasteful" },
	{ "question": "独自", "answers": [ "どくじ" ], "comment": "original; unique; distinctive; characteristic; peculiar\nindependent; one's own; personal" },
	{ "question": "玉", "answers": [ "ぎょく", "たま" ], "comment": "ball; sphere; globe; orb\nbead (of sweat, dew, etc.); drop; droplet\nball (in sports)\npile (of noodles, etc.)\nbullet\nbulb (i.e. a light bulb)\nlens (of glasses, etc.)\nbead (of an abacus)\nball (i.e. a testicle)\ngem; jewel (esp. spherical; sometimes used figuratively); pearl\nfemale entertainer (e.g. a geisha)\nperson (when commenting on their nature); character\nitem, funds or person used as part of a plot\negg\ncoin\nprecious; beautiful; excellent\nprecious stone (esp. jade)\negg (sometimes esp. as a sushi topping)\nstock or security being traded; product being bought or sold\nposition (in finance, the amount of a security either owned or owed by an investor or dealer)\ngeisha\ntime charge for a geisha\nking (of the junior player)" },
	{ "question": "玉子", "answers": [ "たまご" ], "comment": "hen egg" },
	{ "question": "玉石", "answers": [ "たまいし", "ぎょくせき" ], "comment": "gems and stones; wheat and chaff; wheat and tares; good and bad\npebble; round stone; boulder" },
	{ "question": "玉虫", "answers": [ "たまむし" ], "comment": "jewel beetle; Chrysochroa fulgidissima; insect with iridescent wings" },
	{ "question": "王", "answers": [ "おう" ], "comment": "king; ruler; sovereign; monarch\ntycoon; magnate; champion; master\nking (of the senior player)\nemperor; king; prince" },
	{ "question": "王女", "answers": [ "おうじょ" ], "comment": "princess" },
	{ "question": "王子", "answers": [ "おうじ" ], "comment": "prince\nsubordinate Kumano shrine" },
	{ "question": "王手", "answers": [ "おうて" ], "comment": "check" },
	{ "question": "王立", "answers": [ "おうりつ" ], "comment": "royal" },
	{ "question": "生", "answers": [ "なま", "き", "しょう", "せい" ], "comment": "pure; undiluted; raw; crude\nraw; uncooked; fresh\nnatural; as it is; unedited; unprocessed\nunprotected (i.e. not wearing a condom)\nlive (i.e. not recorded)\ninexperienced; unpolished; green; crude\nimpudence; sauciness\nunpasteurized beer; draft beer; draught beer\njust a little; somehow; vaguely; partially; somewhat; half-; semi-\nirresponsibly; half-baked\ncash\ntipsiness\ninnocent; naive; unsophisticated; inexperienced; green; wet behind the ears\nbirth-\nlife; living\nI; me; myself\nvital; virile; lively\narea of thick growth (of trees, grass, etc.)\nboiled and half-dried bonito" },
	{ "question": "生々しい", "answers": [ "なまなましい" ], "comment": "lively; green; fresh; raw; vivid; graphic" },
	{ "question": "生える", "answers": [ "はえる" ], "comment": "to grow; to spring up; to sprout\nto cut (teeth)" },
	{ "question": "生え出る", "answers": [ "はえでる" ], "comment": "to sprout; to spring up; to come out" },
	{ "question": "生かす", "answers": [ "いかす" ], "comment": "to make (the best) use of; to leverage (skills, attributes, experience, etc.); to capitalise on (experience, etc)\nto let live; to keep alive\nto revive; to resuscitate" },
	{ "question": "生きる", "answers": [ "いきる" ], "comment": "to live; to exist\nto make a living; to subsist\nto be in effect; to be in use; to function\nto come to life; to be enlivened\nto be safe (in baseball, go, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "生ける", "answers": [ "いける" ], "comment": "to arrange (flowers); to plant\nliving; live" },
	{ "question": "生じる", "answers": [ "しょうじる" ], "comment": "to produce; to yield; to cause\nto result from; to arise; to be generated" },
	{ "question": "生まれる", "answers": [ "うまれる" ], "comment": "to be born" },
	{ "question": "生まれ年", "answers": [ "うまれどし" ] },
	{ "question": "生まれ月", "answers": [ "うまれづき" ] },
	{ "question": "生み出す", "answers": [ "うみだす" ], "comment": "to create; to bring forth; to produce\nto invent; to think up and bring into being\nto give birth to; to bear" },
	{ "question": "生む", "answers": [ "うむ" ], "comment": "to give birth; to bear (child); to lay (eggs)\nto produce; to yield; to give rise to; to deliver" },
	{ "question": "生やす", "answers": [ "はやす" ], "comment": "to grow; to cultivate; to wear a beard" },
	{ "question": "生年", "answers": [ "せいねん" ], "comment": "year of a person's birth\nnumber of years since one's birth; age" },
	{ "question": "生年月日", "answers": [ "せいねんがっぴ" ], "comment": "birth date; date of birth; DOB" },
	{ "question": "生徒", "answers": [ "せいと" ], "comment": "pupil" },
	{ "question": "生木", "answers": [ "なまき" ], "comment": "live tree; green wood" },
	{ "question": "生気", "answers": [ "せいき" ], "comment": "life; vitality; verve; vigor; vigour; animation; spirit" },
	{ "question": "用件", "answers": [ "ようけん" ], "comment": "business; thing to be done; something that should be performed; information that should be conveyed" },
	{ "question": "田", "answers": [ "た" ], "comment": "rice field" },
	{ "question": "田んぼ", "answers": [ "たんぼ" ], "comment": "paddy field; farm" },
	{ "question": "由来", "answers": [ "ゆらい" ], "comment": "origin; source; history; derivation; reason; destiny" },
	{ "question": "男", "answers": [ "おとこ" ], "comment": "man; male\nfellow; guy; chap; bloke\nmale lover; boyfriend; man\nmanliness; manly honor; manly honour; manly reputation\nman; boy\nmale; man\nhusband\nson" },
	{ "question": "男女", "answers": [ "だんじょ", "おとこおんな" ], "comment": "men and women; man and woman; both sexes; both genders\nmasculine woman; mannish woman\nfeminine man; effeminate man\nintersexual; hermaphrodite" },
	{ "question": "男子", "answers": [ "だんし" ], "comment": "youth; young man" },
	{ "question": "男手", "answers": [ "おとこで" ], "comment": "male help; male labor; male labour\nman's handwriting\nkanji\nman'yōgana written in kaisho or gyōsho style" },
	{ "question": "町", "answers": [ "まち", "ちょう" ], "comment": "town; block; neighbourhood; neighborhood\nstreet; road\n109.09 m\n0.99 hectares" },
	{ "question": "町中", "answers": [ "まちなか", "まちじゅう" ], "comment": "downtown\nthe whole town; all over the town; throughout the town" },
	{ "question": "町人", "answers": [ "ちょうにん" ], "comment": "townspeople; townsfolk; commoner; civilian; merchant; tradesman; tradeswoman; tradespeople; artisan; members of the lowest Edo-period social class (comprising commoners not involved in farming)" },
	{ "question": "病院", "answers": [ "びょういん" ], "comment": "hospital" },
	{ "question": "発車", "answers": [ "はっしゃ" ], "comment": "departure of a vehicle" },
	{ "question": "登山", "answers": [ "とざん" ], "comment": "mountain climbing" },
	{ "question": "白", "answers": [ "しろ" ], "comment": "white\ninnocence; innocent person\nblank space\nwhite go stone\nwhite dragon tile\nskewered grilled pig intestine\nwhite\nunseasoned; undyed; unaltered\nvery much; precisely\nplaying dumb\nunfeigned; honest; diligent\nwhite\nstriped mullet fry (Mugil cephalus)\nspeech; one's lines\nwhite dragon tile\nwhite person; Caucasian\nBelgium" },
	{ "question": "白々しい", "answers": [ "しらじらしい" ], "comment": "barefaced (e.g. lie); shameless; transparent\npure white; very clear" },
	{ "question": "白々と", "answers": [ "しらじらと", "しろじろと" ] },
	{ "question": "白い", "answers": [ "しろい" ], "comment": "white" },
	{ "question": "白ける", "answers": [ "しらける" ], "comment": "to be spoiled (spoilt); to be dampened; to become subdued (e.g. lively atmosphere); to be unamused or bored; to become apathetic\nto fade; to turn white; to grow light (at dawn)" },
	{ "question": "白む", "answers": [ "しらむ" ], "comment": "to grow light; to become white; to turn grey (gray)" },
	{ "question": "白ワイン", "answers": [ "しろわいん" ], "comment": "white wine" },
	{ "question": "白人", "answers": [ "はくじん" ], "comment": "white person; Caucasian" },
	{ "question": "白日", "answers": [ "はくじつ" ], "comment": "bright sunshine; broad daylight" },
	{ "question": "白木", "answers": [ "しらき" ], "comment": "plain wood; unfinished woodwork" },
	{ "question": "白目", "answers": [ "しろめ" ], "comment": "white of the eye\ncold, unwelcoming eyes\npewter; solder" },
	{ "question": "白糸", "answers": [ "しらいと" ], "comment": "white thread" },
	{ "question": "白金", "answers": [ "はっきん" ], "comment": "platinum (Pt)\nsilver (Ag)\nsilver coin; money\nsilver medal\nsilver colour; silver color\nbank\nsilver general" },
	{ "question": "百", "answers": [ "ひゃく" ], "comment": "100; hundred" },
	{ "question": "百人力", "answers": [ "ひゃくにんりき" ], "comment": "tremendous strength" },
	{ "question": "的中", "answers": [ "てきちゅう" ], "comment": "striking home; hitting the mark\ncoming true; proving to be right; becoming realized" },
	{ "question": "的確", "answers": [ "てきかく" ], "comment": "precise; accurate; appropriate; exactly the right" },
	{ "question": "目", "answers": [ "め", "もく" ], "comment": "eye; eyeball\neyesight; sight; vision\nlook; stare; glance\nan experience\nviewpoint\nstitch; texture; weave\nordinal number suffix\nsomewhat; -ish\norder\nitem (of a budget revision, etc.)\ncounter for go pieces; counter for surrounded positions (in go)" },
	{ "question": "目する", "answers": [ "もくする" ], "comment": "to recognize; to recognise; to distinguish\nto pay attention to" },
	{ "question": "目の子", "answers": [ "めのこ" ] },
	{ "question": "目ぼしい", "answers": [ "めぼしい" ], "comment": "main; chief; important; valuable; conspicuous; notable" },
	{ "question": "目まぐるしい", "answers": [ "めまぐるしい" ], "comment": "hectic; bewildering; bustling; dizzy" },
	{ "question": "目上", "answers": [ "めうえ" ], "comment": "superior; superiors; senior" },
	{ "question": "目下", "answers": [ "めした", "もっか" ], "comment": "subordinate; subordinates; inferior; inferiors; junior\nat present; now" },
	{ "question": "目先", "answers": [ "めさき" ], "comment": "before one's eyes; under one's nose\nimmediate (e.g. interests); present; at hand; short-run\nforesight; near future\nappearance" },
	{ "question": "目印", "answers": [ "めじるし" ], "comment": "mark; sign; landmark; benchmark" },
	{ "question": "目玉", "answers": [ "めだま" ], "comment": "eyeball\nspecial feature; centerpiece; showpiece; drawcard\nspecial program; loss leader\nsunny-side-up fried eggs" },
	{ "question": "目見え", "answers": [ "めみえ" ], "comment": "interview\nstage debut; first appearance\nmeeting\ntrial for a servant" },
	{ "question": "直径", "answers": [ "ちょっけい" ], "comment": "diameter" },
	{ "question": "相手", "answers": [ "あいて" ], "comment": "companion; partner; company\nother party; addressee\nopponent (sports, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "省く", "answers": [ "はぶく" ], "comment": "to omit; to leave out; to exclude; to eliminate\nto curtail; to save; to cut down; to economize; to economise" },
	{ "question": "県道", "answers": [ "けんどう" ], "comment": "prefectural road" },
	{ "question": "着地", "answers": [ "ちゃくち" ], "comment": "landing" },
	{ "question": "着物", "answers": [ "きもの" ], "comment": "clothing; clothes\nkimono (or other trad. Japanese clothing)" },
	{ "question": "矢", "answers": [ "や" ], "comment": "arrow\nwedge; chock" },
	{ "question": "短い", "answers": [ "みじかい" ], "comment": "short" },
	{ "question": "石", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "stone\ngem; jewel\nmeasure of volume (approx. 180.39 liters, 6.37 cub. ft.)\nmeasure of a Japanese-style boat's loading capacity (approx. 278.26 liters)" },
	{ "question": "石ころ", "answers": [ "いしころ" ], "comment": "stone; rock; pebble" },
	{ "question": "石目", "answers": [ "いしめ" ] },
	{ "question": "研究", "answers": [ "けんきゅう" ], "comment": "study; research; investigation" },
	{ "question": "破る", "answers": [ "やぶる" ], "comment": "to tear; to break; to destroy\nto break through (opponent's defense etc.); to breach\nto defeat; to beat\nto shatter (dream, peace, etc.); to disturb\nto violate (a rule etc.); to break (a promise etc.)\nto break (a record)" },
	{ "question": "祝福", "answers": [ "しゅくふく" ], "comment": "blessing" },
	{ "question": "神社", "answers": [ "じんじゃ" ], "comment": "Shinto shrine" },
	{ "question": "禁句", "answers": [ "きんく" ], "comment": "taboo word" },
	{ "question": "秋", "answers": [ "あき" ], "comment": "time; hour; moment\nautumn; fall" },
	{ "question": "移転", "answers": [ "いてん" ], "comment": "moving; relocation; change of address\ntransfer (of deeds, property, etc.); demise" },
	{ "question": "種", "answers": [ "たね" ], "comment": "kind; variety\n(biological) species\n(logical) species\nseed (e.g. of a plant); pip; kind; variety; quality; tone\nmaterial (e.g. for an article); matter (e.g. of a story); subject; theme; (news) copy\ningredient; leaven (bread); main ingredient of a sushi\ncause; source\ntrick; secret; magician's trick; inside story\npaternal blood; lineage\nbreed (of a stock); sperm; semen\ncause; seed; origin\nvariety; kind\ncounter for varieties" },
	{ "question": "種類", "answers": [ "しゅるい" ], "comment": "variety; kind; type; category\ncounter for different sorts of things" },
	{ "question": "空", "answers": [ "そら", "から", "くう" ], "comment": "emptiness; vacuum; blank\nsky; the air; the heavens\nweather\nfar-off place; distant place\nstate of mind; feeling\n(from) memory; (by) heart\nfalsehood; lie\nsomehow; vaguely\nfake\nhollow; cavity; hole\nempty air; sky\nshunyata; emptiness; the lack of an immutable intrinsic nature within any phenomenon\nair force\nfruitlessness; meaninglessness\nvoid (one of the five elements)\nempty (e.g. set)" },
	{ "question": "空く", "answers": [ "あく", "すく" ], "comment": "to become less crowded; to thin out; to get empty\nto be hungry\nto open (e.g. doors)\nto open (e.g. business, etc.)\nto be empty\nto be vacant; to be available; to be free\nto be open (e.g. neckline, etc.)\nto have been opened (of one's eyes, mouth, etc.)\nto come to an end\nto open (one's eyes, mouth, etc.)\nto have a hole; to form a gap; to have an interval (between events)" },
	{ "question": "空ける", "answers": [ "あける" ], "comment": "to empty; to remove; to make space; to make room\nto move out; to clear out\nto be away from (e.g. one's house); to leave (temporarily)\nto dawn; to grow light\nto end (of a period, season)\nto begin (of the New Year)\nto leave (one's schedule) open; to make time (for)\nto make (a hole); to open up (a hole)\nto become empty (hollow)\nto relax from a tense situation into a vacant or absent minded state" },
	{ "question": "空中", "answers": [ "くうちゅう" ], "comment": "sky; air" },
	{ "question": "空名", "answers": [ "くうめい" ], "comment": "empty name; false reputation" },
	{ "question": "空手", "answers": [ "からて" ], "comment": "karate\nempty handed" },
	{ "question": "空文", "answers": [ "くうぶん" ], "comment": "dead letter" },
	{ "question": "空気", "answers": [ "くうき" ], "comment": "air; atmosphere\nmood; situation\nsomeone with no presence; someone who doesn't stand out at all" },
	{ "question": "空白", "answers": [ "くうはく" ], "comment": "blank space; vacuum; space; null (NUL)" },
	{ "question": "空車", "answers": [ "くうしゃ", "からぐるま" ], "comment": "empty conveyance; free taxi\nparking lot with spaces available" },
	{ "question": "立ち上がる", "answers": [ "たちあがる" ], "comment": "to stand up; to get up\nto rise\nto recover\nto take action; to start\nto make the initial charge\nto start up; to boot up" },
	{ "question": "立ち入り", "answers": [ "たちいり" ], "comment": "entering; going into" },
	{ "question": "立ち木", "answers": [ "たちき" ], "comment": "standing tree; standing timber" },
	{ "question": "立ち見", "answers": [ "たちみ" ], "comment": "standing watching a performance; standing and looking at something" },
	{ "question": "立つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to stand; to rise; to stand up\nto find oneself (e.g. in a difficult position)\nto depart (on a plane, train, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "立てる", "answers": [ "たてる" ], "comment": "to stand up; to put up; to set up; to erect; to raise\nto thrust into; to bury into; to dig into\nto make (a noise); to start (a rumour); to raise (a cloud of dust, etc.); to cause\nto make; to establish; to set up; to develop; to formulate\nto put up (a political candidate); to make (one's leader)\nto treat with respect; to give (someone) their due; to make (someone) look good; to avoid embarrassing (someone)\nto sharpen; to make clear\nto shut; to close\nto make tea (matcha); to perform the tea ceremony\nto divide by\nto do ... vigorously" },
	{ "question": "立て石", "answers": [ "たていし" ], "comment": "milestone; standing stone" },
	{ "question": "竹", "answers": [ "たけ" ], "comment": "bamboo\nmiddle (of a three-tier ranking system)" },
	{ "question": "竹の子", "answers": [ "たけのこ" ], "comment": "bamboo shoot\ninexperienced doctor; quack" },
	{ "question": "竹林", "answers": [ "ちくりん", "たけばやし" ], "comment": "bamboo thicket" },
	{ "question": "筆", "answers": [ "ふで" ], "comment": "writing brush" },
	{ "question": "答える", "answers": [ "こたえる" ], "comment": "to answer; to reply" },
	{ "question": "算数", "answers": [ "さんすう" ], "comment": "arithmetic" },
	{ "question": "箱", "answers": [ "はこ" ], "comment": "box; case; chest; package; pack; crate\ncar (of a train, etc.)\nshamisen case; shamisen\npublic building; community building\nman who carries a geisha's shamisen\nreceptacle for human waste; feces (faeces)\ncounter for boxes (or boxed objects)" },
	{ "question": "米俵", "answers": [ "こめだわら" ], "comment": "bag of rice" },
	{ "question": "粉末", "answers": [ "ふんまつ" ], "comment": "fine powder" },
	{ "question": "糸", "answers": [ "いと", "し" ], "comment": "thread; yarn; string\nthread\n0.001; one ten-thousandth" },
	{ "question": "糸口", "answers": [ "いとぐち" ], "comment": "thread end\nbeginning\nclue" },
	{ "question": "糸目", "answers": [ "いとめ" ], "comment": "fine line\nweight of thread\nslit-eyed" },
	{ "question": "糸車", "answers": [ "いとぐるま" ], "comment": "spinning wheel" },
	{ "question": "約束", "answers": [ "やくそく" ], "comment": "promise; agreement; arrangement; one's word; contract; pact; appointment; engagement; date\nconvention; rule\ndestiny; fate" },
	{ "question": "細い", "answers": [ "ほそい" ], "comment": "thin; slender; fine\nunlucky (billiards slang)\nsmall; fine; minute\nstingy; cheap" },
	{ "question": "統一", "answers": [ "とういつ" ], "comment": "unity; consolidation; uniformity; unification; compatible" },
	{ "question": "絵", "answers": [ "え" ], "comment": "picture; drawing; painting; sketch" },
	{ "question": "続ける", "answers": [ "つづける" ], "comment": "to continue; to keep up; to keep on" },
	{ "question": "線路", "answers": [ "せんろ" ], "comment": "railway track; railway line; railroad; railway; track; line" },
	{ "question": "編集", "answers": [ "へんしゅう" ], "comment": "editing; compilation; editorial (e.g. committee)" },
	{ "question": "練習", "answers": [ "れんしゅう" ], "comment": "practice; practising" },
	{ "question": "義務", "answers": [ "ぎむ" ], "comment": "duty; obligation; responsibility" },
	{ "question": "羽", "answers": [ "はね" ], "comment": "feather; plume; down\nwing\nblade (of a fan, propeller, etc.)\nshuttlecock\ncounter for birds and rabbits\nfifth degree (of the Japanese & Chinese pentatonic scale)" },
	{ "question": "考える", "answers": [ "かんがえる" ], "comment": "to think about; to take into consideration\nto ponder; to reflect; to try to come at a conclusion; to think over (something)\nto intend; to decide (to do); to plan\nto come up with; to devise; to scheme\nto predict; to anticipate; to expect\nto suspect; to doubt\nto consider (somebody to be something); to look on" },
	{ "question": "耳", "answers": [ "みみ" ], "comment": "ear\nhearing\nedge; crust\nselvedge (non-fray machined edge of fabrics); selvage" },
	{ "question": "耳目", "answers": [ "じもく" ], "comment": "eye and ear\none's attention; one's interest" },
	{ "question": "聞く", "answers": [ "きく" ], "comment": "to hear\nto listen (e.g. to music)\nto ask; to enquire; to query\nto learn of; to hear about\nto follow (advice); to comply with\nto smell (esp. incense); to sample fragrance" },
	{ "question": "職責", "answers": [ "しょくせき" ], "comment": "one's duty; responsibilities pertaining to one's work" },
	{ "question": "肥料", "answers": [ "ひりょう" ], "comment": "manure; fertilizer; fertiliser" },
	{ "question": "育つ", "answers": [ "そだつ" ], "comment": "to be raised (e.g. child); to be brought up; to grow (up)" },
	{ "question": "能力", "answers": [ "のうりょく" ], "comment": "ability; faculty\nlow-ranking priest who does manual labour at a temple; male temple employee" },
	{ "question": "腸", "answers": [ "ちょう" ], "comment": "guts; bowels; intestines" },
	{ "question": "興味", "answers": [ "きょうみ" ], "comment": "interest (in something); curiosity (about something); zest (for)" },
	{ "question": "花", "answers": [ "はな" ], "comment": "flower; blossom; bloom; petal\ncherry blossom\nbeauty\nblooming (esp. of cherry blossoms)\nikebana\nJapanese playing cards\n(the) best" },
	{ "question": "花火", "answers": [ "はなび" ], "comment": "fireworks" },
	{ "question": "花見", "answers": [ "はなみ" ], "comment": "cherry blossom viewing; flower viewing" },
	{ "question": "芸", "answers": [ "げい" ], "comment": "art; craft; accomplishment; artistic skill; technique; performance" },
	{ "question": "芽", "answers": [ "め" ], "comment": "sprout" },
	{ "question": "苦しい", "answers": [ "くるしい" ], "comment": "painful; difficult; agonizing\nneedy; tight (budget); straitened (circumstances)\nforced (smile, joke); lame (excuse); strained (interpretation)\nawkward (situation); painful (position)\n(after masu stem) hard to do; unpleasant" },
	{ "question": "英語", "answers": [ "えいご" ], "comment": "English (language)" },
	{ "question": "茶", "answers": [ "ちゃ" ], "comment": "tea\ntea plant (Camellia sinensis)\ntea preparation; making tea\nbrown\nmockery" },
	{ "question": "草", "answers": [ "くさ" ], "comment": "grass; weed; herb; thatch\nninja\nnot genuine; substandard\nlaughter; LOL\ndraft; rough copy\ncursive script; \"grass\" kanji" },
	{ "question": "草木", "answers": [ "くさき", "そうもく" ], "comment": "plants; vegetation" },
	{ "question": "草本", "answers": [ "そうほん" ], "comment": "herbaceous plant; herb" },
	{ "question": "草花", "answers": [ "くさばな", "そうか" ], "comment": "flower; flowering plant" },
	{ "question": "荷物", "answers": [ "にもつ" ], "comment": "luggage; baggage; package\nburden\npayload (of a packet, cell, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "落石", "answers": [ "らくせき" ], "comment": "falling rocks; fallen rocks" },
	{ "question": "虫", "answers": [ "むし" ], "comment": "insect; bug; cricket; moth; worm" },
	{ "question": "虫歯", "answers": [ "むしば" ], "comment": "cavity; tooth decay; decayed tooth; dental caries" },
	{ "question": "血", "answers": [ "ち" ], "comment": "blood; consanguinity" },
	{ "question": "衛生", "answers": [ "えいせい" ], "comment": "health; hygiene; sanitation; medical" },
	{ "question": "表示", "answers": [ "ひょうじ" ], "comment": "indication; expression; showing; manifestation; demonstration\ndisplay; displaying\nrepresentation" },
	{ "question": "複数", "answers": [ "ふくすう" ], "comment": "several; plural; plurality; multiple" },
	{ "question": "西", "answers": [ "にし" ], "comment": "west\nSpain" },
	{ "question": "見", "answers": [ "けん" ], "comment": "looking; viewing\nview (of life, etc.); outlook" },
	{ "question": "見える", "answers": [ "みえる" ], "comment": "to be seen; to be in sight\nto look; to seem; to appear\nto come\nto have an audience; to meet; to see\nto face (an enemy); to confront\nto serve (esp. as one's wife)" },
	{ "question": "見え見え", "answers": [ "みえみえ" ], "comment": "obvious; transparent" },
	{ "question": "見せる", "answers": [ "みせる" ], "comment": "to show; to display" },
	{ "question": "見た目", "answers": [ "みため" ], "comment": "appearance" },
	{ "question": "見る", "answers": [ "みる" ], "comment": "to see; to look; to watch; to view; to observe\nto look over; to look on; to assess; to examine; to judge\nto look after; to keep an eye on; to take care of\nto view (e.g. flowers, movie)\nto try; to try out; to test\nto see that...; to find that..." },
	{ "question": "見る目", "answers": [ "みるめ" ], "comment": "public opinion; public eye; (in) the eyes of others\ndiscerning eye; an eye (for sth)\nperspective; way of looking at things; point of view" },
	{ "question": "見る見る", "answers": [ "みるみる" ], "comment": "very fast; in a twinkle; before one's eyes" },
	{ "question": "見上げる", "answers": [ "みあげる" ], "comment": "to look up at; to raise one's eyes\nto look up to; to admire; to respect" },
	{ "question": "見下す", "answers": [ "みくだす" ], "comment": "to despise; to look down on" },
	{ "question": "見下ろす", "answers": [ "みおろす" ], "comment": "to overlook; to command a view of; to look down on\nto despise; to look down on" },
	{ "question": "見入る", "answers": [ "みいる" ], "comment": "to gaze at; to fix one's eyes upon" },
	{ "question": "見出し", "answers": [ "みだし" ], "comment": "heading; headline; title; caption\nindex\nheadword" },
	{ "question": "見出す", "answers": [ "みいだす" ], "comment": "to find out; to discover; to notice; to detect\nto select; to pick out\nto look out (from the inside)\nto be wide-eyed (in surprise, anger, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "見学", "answers": [ "けんがく" ], "comment": "inspection; study by observation; field trip" },
	{ "question": "見本", "answers": [ "みほん" ], "comment": "sample; specimen; pattern\nmodel; example" },
	{ "question": "見目", "answers": [ "みめ" ], "comment": "appearance; looks" },
	{ "question": "規定", "answers": [ "きてい" ], "comment": "stipulation; prescription; provision; regulation; rule" },
	{ "question": "親しい", "answers": [ "したしい" ], "comment": "intimate; close (e.g. friend)\nintimate; close" },
	{ "question": "観察", "answers": [ "かんさつ" ], "comment": "observation; survey; watching" },
	{ "question": "観戦", "answers": [ "かんせん" ], "comment": "watching a (sports) game; spectating; observing (military operations)" },
	{ "question": "角", "answers": [ "つの", "かど" ], "comment": "angle\nsquare (or cube)\nbishop\nthird degree (of the Japanese & Chinese pentatonic scale)\nChinese \"horn\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\njiao (monetary unit of China; one-tenth of a yuan)\ncorner (e.g. desk, pavement)\nedge\nhorn\ncorner; nook; recess\ndownstage right (on a noh stage)" },
	{ "question": "言う", "answers": [ "いう", "ゆう" ], "comment": "to say; to utter; to declare\nto name; to call\nto go (e.g. \"the alarm went ping\"); to make a noise" },
	{ "question": "計算", "answers": [ "けいさん" ], "comment": "calculation; reckoning; count\nforecast" },
	{ "question": "訓練", "answers": [ "くんれん" ], "comment": "practice; practising; training" },
	{ "question": "記入", "answers": [ "きにゅう" ], "comment": "entry; filling in of forms" },
	{ "question": "記録", "answers": [ "きろく" ], "comment": "record; minutes; document\nrecord (e.g. in sports); results; score\nto record; to document\nto set a record (e.g. in sports); to show a result; to reach a value" },
	{ "question": "許可", "answers": [ "きょか" ], "comment": "permission; approval; authorization; license\nto permit; to authorize" },
	{ "question": "評価", "answers": [ "ひょうか" ], "comment": "valuation; estimation; assessment; evaluation; rating\nto value; to assess; to rate; to estimate value\nto appreciate; to value highly; to acknowledge the value (of something)" },
	{ "question": "評判", "answers": [ "ひょうばん" ], "comment": "fame; reputation; popularity\nrumour (rumor); talk" },
	{ "question": "試合", "answers": [ "しあい" ], "comment": "match; game; bout; contest" },
	{ "question": "詩情", "answers": [ "しじょう" ], "comment": "poetic sentiment; poetic interest" },
	{ "question": "説得", "answers": [ "せっとく" ], "comment": "persuasion" },
	{ "question": "調子", "answers": [ "ちょうし" ], "comment": "tune; tone; key; pitch; time; rhythm\nvein; mood; way; manner; style; knack\ncondition; state of health\nimpetus; spur of the moment; strain\ntrend" },
	{ "question": "調査", "answers": [ "ちょうさ" ], "comment": "investigation; examination; inquiry; enquiry; survey" },
	{ "question": "講師", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "lecturer" },
	{ "question": "謝礼", "answers": [ "しゃれい" ], "comment": "reward; honorarium; remuneration" },
	{ "question": "謝罪", "answers": [ "しゃざい" ], "comment": "apology" },
	{ "question": "豊作", "answers": [ "ほうさく" ], "comment": "abundant harvest; bumper crop" },
	{ "question": "豊富", "answers": [ "ほうふ" ], "comment": "abundance; wealth; plenty; bounty" },
	{ "question": "貝", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "shellfish\nseashell; shell\nJapanese babylon (species of shelled mollusk, Babylonia japonica); Japanese ivory shell\nspinning top (traditionally made from a Japanese babylon shell)" },
	{ "question": "財力", "answers": [ "ざいりょく" ], "comment": "assets" },
	{ "question": "貧しい", "answers": [ "まずしい" ], "comment": "poor; needy\nlacking (quantity and quality-wise); poor; scanty; skimpy; slight; inadequate" },
	{ "question": "責任", "answers": [ "せきにん" ], "comment": "duty; responsibility (incl. supervision of staff)\nliability; onus" },
	{ "question": "貯金", "answers": [ "ちょきん" ], "comment": "putting money aside; savings; deposit (e.g. in a bank)\naccumulated surplus of wins; wins in the bank" },
	{ "question": "買う", "answers": [ "かう" ], "comment": "to buy; to purchase\nto value; to have a high opinion\nto stir; to provoke" },
	{ "question": "費用", "answers": [ "ひよう" ], "comment": "cost; expense" },
	{ "question": "貿易", "answers": [ "ぼうえき" ], "comment": "trade (foreign)" },
	{ "question": "賛同", "answers": [ "さんどう" ], "comment": "approval; endorsement" },
	{ "question": "質", "answers": [ "しつ" ], "comment": "quality; value\nnature; inherent quality; character\nlogical quality\nquality; nature (of person)\ncollateral; pledge; pawned article" },
	{ "question": "赤", "answers": [ "あか" ], "comment": "red; crimson; scarlet\nred-containing colour (e.g. brown, pink, orange)\nRed (i.e. communist)\nred light\nred ink (i.e. in finance or proof-reading); (in) the red\ncomplete; total; perfect; obvious\ncopper" },
	{ "question": "赤々と", "answers": [ "あかあかと" ] },
	{ "question": "赤い", "answers": [ "あかい" ], "comment": "red\nRed (i.e. communist)" },
	{ "question": "赤ちゃん", "answers": [ "あかちゃん" ], "comment": "baby; infant" },
	{ "question": "赤らむ", "answers": [ "あからむ" ], "comment": "to become red; to redden; to blush" },
	{ "question": "赤らめる", "answers": [ "あからめる" ], "comment": "to blush; to redden" },
	{ "question": "赤子", "answers": [ "あかご", "せきし" ], "comment": "baby\nimperial children; imperial child" },
	{ "question": "赤字", "answers": [ "あかじ" ], "comment": "deficit; (being in or going into) the red\nred text; red letters\ncorrections (by a teacher or proofreader) written in red" },
	{ "question": "赤本", "answers": [ "あかほん" ], "comment": "pulp fiction\nworkbook for college exam takers (published by Kyougakusha)" },
	{ "question": "赤水", "answers": [ "あかみず" ] },
	{ "question": "赤目", "answers": [ "あかめ" ], "comment": "red eyes; bloodshot eyes\nred-eye\nred mullet (Chelon haematocheilus)\nfacial gesture of pulling one's eyelid down and sticking out one's tongue\nfacial gesture of pulling one's eyelid down and sticking out one's tongue" },
	{ "question": "赤虫", "answers": [ "あかむし" ], "comment": "bloodworm (Halla okadai, species of eunicid worm used as fishing bait)\nred mite (Trombicula akamushi); chigger mite; harvest mite" },
	{ "question": "走る", "answers": [ "はしる" ], "comment": "to run\nto travel (movement of vehicles); to drive\nto hurry to\nto retreat (from battle); to take flight\nto run away from home\nto elope\nto tend heavily toward\nto flash; to streak; to shoot through (e.g. pain)" },
	{ "question": "起きる", "answers": [ "おきる" ], "comment": "to get up; to rise; to blaze up (fire)\nto wake up; to be awake; to stay awake\nto occur (usu. of unfavourable incidents); to happen; to take place" },
	{ "question": "足", "answers": [ "あし" ], "comment": "foot\nleg\ngait\npace\nbottom structural component (i.e. radical) of a kanji\nmeans of transportation\nmoney; coin\ncounter for pairs (of socks, shoes, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "足す", "answers": [ "たす" ], "comment": "to add (numbers)\nto add (something); to top up (with something)\nto take care of (e.g. one's business)" },
	{ "question": "足りる", "answers": [ "たりる" ], "comment": "to be sufficient; to be enough\nto be worth doing; to be worthy\nto be sufficient; to answer; to do" },
	{ "question": "足る", "answers": [ "たる" ], "comment": "to be sufficient; to be enough; to be worthy of" },
	{ "question": "足下", "answers": [ "あしもと", "そっか" ], "comment": "at one's feet; underfoot; one's step (as in \"watch your step\")\ngait; pace; step\nmost recent; current\nyou; thou" },
	{ "question": "足先", "answers": [ "あしさき" ], "comment": "part of the feet from the ankles to the tips of the toes" },
	{ "question": "足早", "answers": [ "あしばや" ], "comment": "quick-footed; light-footed; quick pace" },
	{ "question": "足音", "answers": [ "あしおと" ], "comment": "(sound of) footsteps\nsense or sign that something is approaching" },
	{ "question": "足首", "answers": [ "あしくび" ], "comment": "ankle" },
	{ "question": "車", "answers": [ "くるま" ], "comment": "car; automobile; vehicle\nwheel\ncar; vehicle" },
	{ "question": "車上", "answers": [ "しゃじょう" ], "comment": "on or aboard a train or vehicle" },
	{ "question": "車中", "answers": [ "しゃちゅう" ], "comment": "in a train or vehicle" },
	{ "question": "車輪", "answers": [ "しゃりん" ], "comment": "(car) wheel" },
	{ "question": "軍", "answers": [ "ぐん" ], "comment": "army; force; troops\nwar; battle; campaign; fight\ntroops; forces" },
	{ "question": "軽", "answers": [ "かる" ], "comment": "light (e.g. vehicle, aircraft, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "輸出", "answers": [ "ゆしゅつ" ], "comment": "export\nefferent" },
	{ "question": "辞任", "answers": [ "じにん" ], "comment": "resignation (from a position)" },
	{ "question": "近く", "answers": [ "ちかく" ], "comment": "near; neighbourhood; neighborhood; vicinity\nnearly (e.g. \"it took nearly one year\"); close to\nshortly; soon" },
	{ "question": "迷路", "answers": [ "めいろ" ], "comment": "maze; labyrinth; blind alley" },
	{ "question": "通貨", "answers": [ "つうか" ], "comment": "currency" },
	{ "question": "速度", "answers": [ "そくど" ], "comment": "speed; velocity; rate" },
	{ "question": "造花", "answers": [ "ぞうか" ], "comment": "artificial flowers\nartificial flower making" },
	{ "question": "進歩", "answers": [ "しんぽ" ], "comment": "progress; advance; improvement; development" },
	{ "question": "運ぶ", "answers": [ "はこぶ" ], "comment": "to carry; to transport; to move; to convey\nto come; to go\nto wield (a tool, etc.); to use\nto go (well, etc.); to proceed; to progress" },
	{ "question": "運動", "answers": [ "うんどう" ], "comment": "exercise; physical training; work-out\nappeal; campaign; drive; crusade; movement; lobbying\nmotion; movement" },
	{ "question": "過度", "answers": [ "かど" ], "comment": "excess; immoderation" },
	{ "question": "道具", "answers": [ "どうぐ" ], "comment": "tool; implement; instrument; utensil; apparatus; device\nmeans" },
	{ "question": "達意", "answers": [ "たつい" ], "comment": "lucidity; intelligibility; perspicuity" },
	{ "question": "達成", "answers": [ "たっせい" ], "comment": "achievement" },
	{ "question": "達観", "answers": [ "たっかん" ], "comment": "taking a philosophic view\nlooking at the long term; farsightedness" },
	{ "question": "遠足", "answers": [ "えんそく" ], "comment": "excursion; outing; trip" },
	{ "question": "選ぶ", "answers": [ "えらぶ" ], "comment": "to choose; to select" },
	{ "question": "部品", "answers": [ "ぶひん" ], "comment": "parts; accessories; components" },
	{ "question": "都合", "answers": [ "つごう" ], "comment": "circumstances; condition; convenience\nto arrange; to manage\nto lend money; to raise money\nin all; in total; all told" },
	{ "question": "配る", "answers": [ "くばる" ], "comment": "to distribute; to deliver; to deal (cards)" },
	{ "question": "酒", "answers": [ "さけ" ], "comment": "alcohol; sake" },
	{ "question": "酒税", "answers": [ "しゅぜい" ], "comment": "liquor tax; tax on alcohol" },
	{ "question": "重圧", "answers": [ "じゅうあつ" ], "comment": "strong pressure; heavy pressure" },
	{ "question": "野原", "answers": [ "のはら" ], "comment": "field" },
	{ "question": "野球", "answers": [ "やきゅう" ], "comment": "baseball" },
	{ "question": "野菜", "answers": [ "やさい" ], "comment": "vegetable" },
	{ "question": "金", "answers": [ "きん", "かね" ], "comment": "gold\nmoney\nmetal\ngold (Au); golden (color); gold (medal, cup)\nvaluable; of highest value\nmoney; gold coin (orig. meaning)\nFriday\nmetal (fourth of the five elements)\nJin (dynasty of China; 1115-1234 CE)\ngold general\ntesticles\nkarat; carat" },
	{ "question": "金メダル", "answers": [ "きんめだる" ], "comment": "gold medal" },
	{ "question": "金力", "answers": [ "きんりょく" ], "comment": "monetary power" },
	{ "question": "金庫", "answers": [ "きんこ" ], "comment": "safe; strongbox; cashbox; vault; strongroom\ndepository; cash office; treasury; provider of funds\ntreasure house; treasury\nfinancial supporter; patron; financier; backer" },
	{ "question": "金玉", "answers": [ "きんたま", "きんぎょく" ], "comment": "testicles\ngold and jewels; precious object" },
	{ "question": "金目", "answers": [ "かねめ" ], "comment": "monetary value\nEdo-period unit of gold coinage\ngolden eyes (of a cat, etc.)\nsplendid alfonsino (Beryx splendens)" },
	{ "question": "金糸", "answers": [ "きんし" ], "comment": "gold thread" },
	{ "question": "金額", "answers": [ "きんがく" ], "comment": "amount of money" },
	{ "question": "銀", "answers": [ "ぎん" ], "comment": "money\nmetal\nsilver (Ag)\nsilver coin; money\nsilver medal\nsilver colour; silver color\nbank\nsilver general" },
	{ "question": "開ける", "answers": [ "あける", "ひらける" ], "comment": "to open (a door, etc.); to unwrap (e.g. parcel, package); to unlock\nto open (for business, etc.)\nto empty; to remove; to make space; to make room\nto move out; to clear out\nto be away from (e.g. one's house); to leave (temporarily)\nto dawn; to grow light\nto end (of a period, season)\nto begin (of the New Year)\nto leave (one's schedule) open; to make time (for)\nto make (a hole); to open up (a hole)\nto become opened up; to improve; to get better\nto develop; to progress; to become civilized (civilised); to be up-to-date\nto be enlightened; to be sensible\nto open; to bare; to expose\nto stretch" },
	{ "question": "開始", "answers": [ "かいし" ], "comment": "start; commencement; beginning; initiation" },
	{ "question": "関係", "answers": [ "かんけい" ], "comment": "relation; relationship; connection\nparticipation; involvement; concern\ninfluence; effect\nsexual relations; sexual relationship\nrelated to ...; connected to ..." },
	{ "question": "関心", "answers": [ "かんしん" ], "comment": "concern; interest" },
	{ "question": "防止", "answers": [ "ぼうし" ], "comment": "prevention; check" },
	{ "question": "集合", "answers": [ "しゅうごう" ], "comment": "gathering; assembly; meeting\nset" },
	{ "question": "雑草", "answers": [ "ざっそう" ], "comment": "weed" },
	{ "question": "雨", "answers": [ "あめ" ], "comment": "rain" },
	{ "question": "雨天", "answers": [ "うてん" ], "comment": "rainy weather" },
	{ "question": "雨空", "answers": [ "あまぞら" ], "comment": "rainy sky; sky as it looks when it is about to rain; threatening sky" },
	{ "question": "雲", "answers": [ "くも" ], "comment": "cloud" },
	{ "question": "電気", "answers": [ "でんき" ], "comment": "electricity\n(electric) light" },
	{ "question": "青", "answers": [ "あお" ], "comment": "blue\ngreen\ngreen light\nblack (horse coat color)\nimmature; unripe; young" },
	{ "question": "青々と", "answers": [ "あおあおと" ] },
	{ "question": "青い", "answers": [ "あおい" ], "comment": "blue; green\npale\nunripe; inexperienced" },
	{ "question": "青っぽい", "answers": [ "あおっぽい" ], "comment": "bluish; greenish\nimmature; inexperienced; green; naive" },
	{ "question": "青天", "answers": [ "せいてん" ], "comment": "blue sky" },
	{ "question": "青年", "answers": [ "せいねん" ], "comment": "youth; young man" },
	{ "question": "青木", "answers": [ "あおき" ], "comment": "Japanese laurel; spotted laurel; Aucuba japonica\nlive tree" },
	{ "question": "青玉", "answers": [ "せいぎょく" ], "comment": "sapphire; jacinth" },
	{ "question": "青田", "answers": [ "あおた" ], "comment": "green paddy" },
	{ "question": "青白い", "answers": [ "あおじろい" ], "comment": "pale; pallid\nbluish-white" },
	{ "question": "青空", "answers": [ "あおぞら" ], "comment": "blue sky" },
	{ "question": "青竹", "answers": [ "あおだけ" ], "comment": "green bamboo" },
	{ "question": "青草", "answers": [ "あおくさ", "せいそう" ], "comment": "green grass" },
	{ "question": "青虫", "answers": [ "あおむし" ], "comment": "cabbageworm (caterpillar of the cabbage white butterfly)" },
	{ "question": "非力", "answers": [ "ひりき" ], "comment": "powerless; helpless; incompetent" },
	{ "question": "音", "answers": [ "おと", "ね", "おん" ], "comment": "sound; noise; report\nnote\nfame\nChinese-derived character reading" },
	{ "question": "音名", "answers": [ "おんめい" ], "comment": "names of musical notes" },
	{ "question": "順番", "answers": [ "じゅんばん" ], "comment": "turn (in line); order of things; sequential order" },
	{ "question": "領土", "answers": [ "りょうど" ], "comment": "dominion; territory; possession" },
	{ "question": "顔", "answers": [ "かお" ], "comment": "face; visage\nlook; expression; countenance\nhonor; honour; face\ninfluence; notoriety\ncountenance; visage\nface; honor (honour); dignity" },
	{ "question": "願う", "answers": [ "ねがう" ], "comment": "to desire; to wish; to hope\nto beg; to request; to implore; to pray\nto have something done for oneself" },
	{ "question": "風", "answers": [ "かぜ", "ふう" ], "comment": "swing; shake; wave; swinging\nappearance; behaviour\npretence (pretense); show; pretending (to)\ngoing to restaurant, hotel etc. without a reservation or introduction\nmove (dance); postures\nlead in (e.g. to a running joke, asking a question); lead up\nunsewn part of a hanging sleeve on a traditional Japanese woman's garment\ncounter for swords, blades, etc.\nnot wearing underwear or pants\nwind; breeze; draught; draft\nmanner; behaviour; behavior\ncold; influenza\nmethod; manner; way; style\nappearance; air\ntendency\nfolk song (genre of the Shi Jing)\nwind (one of the five elements)" },
	{ "question": "食べる", "answers": [ "たべる" ], "comment": "to eat\nto live on (e.g. a salary); to live off; to subsist on" },
	{ "question": "飼育", "answers": [ "しいく" ], "comment": "breeding; raising; rearing" },
	{ "question": "駅", "answers": [ "えき" ], "comment": "station" },
	{ "question": "高い", "answers": [ "たかい" ], "comment": "high; tall\nexpensive" },
	{ "question": "高潔", "answers": [ "こうけつ" ], "comment": "purity; nobility" },
	{ "question": "魚", "answers": [ "さかな", "うお" ], "comment": "fish" },
	{ "question": "鳥", "answers": [ "とり" ], "comment": "bird\nbird meat (esp. chicken meat); fowl; poultry" },
	{ "question": "黒い", "answers": [ "くろい" ], "comment": "black\ndark\nillicit; wicked; underground" },
	{ "question": "黒板", "answers": [ "こくばん" ], "comment": "blackboard" },
	{ "question": "鼻水", "answers": [ "はなみず" ], "comment": "nasal mucus; dripping nose; snot" }
]
}
